<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WI-Statutes">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-71"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-71"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#wisconsin-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-wi"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71"/>
          <FRBRname value="WI-Statutes"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-71/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-71/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-71/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-71/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="wisconsin-legislature" href="https://docs.legis.wisconsin.gov" showAs="Wisconsin State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_71">
        <num>71</num>
        <heading>Income and Franchise Taxes for State and Local Revenues</heading>
        <section eId="sec_71-01">
          <num>71.01</num>
          <heading>Definitions</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(1)  “Adjusted gross income”, when not preceded by the word “federal”, means Wisconsin adjusted gross income, unless otherwise defined or the context plainly requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_1am">
            <num>(1am)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(1am)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_1as">
            <num>(1as)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(1as)  “Broadcaster” means a television or radio station licensed by the federal communications commission, a television or radio broadcast network, a cable television network, or a television distribution company.  “Broadcaster” does not include a cable service provider, a direct broadcast satellite system, or an Internet content distributor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(1b)  For purposes of s.71.04 (7) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “commercial domicile” means the location from which a trade or business is principally managed and directed, based on any factors the department determines are appropriate, including the location where the greatest number of employees of the trade or business work, have their office or base of operations, or from which the employees are directed or controlled.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_1n">
            <num>(1n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(1n)  For purposes of s.71.04 (7) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “domicile” means an individual’s true, fixed, and permanent home where the individual intends to remain permanently and indefinitely and to which, whenever absent, the individual intends to return, except that no individual may have more than one domicile at any time.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_1t">
            <num>(1t)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(1t)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(2)  “Entertainer” means a nonresident natural person who, for consideration, furnishes amusement, entertainment or public speaking services, or performs in one or more sporting events in this state and includes both employees and independent contractors.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(3)  “Federal net operating loss” of persons other than corporations means net operating loss as determined by the taxpayer under the internal revenue code, or if redetermined by the department, as determined by the department under such code or as may be determined on final appeal therefrom.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(4)  “Federal taxable income” and “federal adjusted gross income” of natural persons and fiduciaries mean taxable income or adjusted gross income as determined under the internal revenue code or, if redetermined by the department, as determined by the department under the internal revenue code or as may be determined on final appeal therefrom.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(5)  “Fiduciary”, “income” and “person” and all other terms not otherwise defined, have the same meaning as in the internal revenue code unless otherwise defined or the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_5g">
            <num>(5g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(5g)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_5m">
            <num>(5m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(5m)  “Head of household” has the meaning given in section2(b) and (c) of the internal revenue code, except that “head of household” includes surviving spouse, as defined in section2(a) of the internal revenue code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_5n">
            <num>(5n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(5n)  For purposes of s.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 46., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing Wisconsin adjusted gross income:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_5p">
            <num>(5p)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(5p)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_5s">
            <num>(5s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(5s)  For purposes of s.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 46., “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code and deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-01__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(6)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-02">
          <num>71.02</num>
          <heading>Imposition of tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_8m">
            <num>(8m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(8m)  “Partner” does not include a partner of a publicly traded partnership treated as a corporation under s.71.22 (1k).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_8r">
            <num>(8r)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(8r)  “Pay”, in regard to submissions to or for the department, means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(9)  “Person” includes natural persons and fiduciaries, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_9ad">
            <num>(9ad)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(9ad)  “Qualified real estate investment trust” has the meaning given in s.71.22 (9ad).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_9am">
            <num>(9am)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(9am)  “Related entity” means any person related to a taxpayer as provided under section267or1563of the Internal Revenue Code during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year and any real estate investment trust under section856of the Internal Revenue Code, except a qualified real estate investment trust, if more than 50 percent of any class of the beneficial interests or shares of the real estate investment trust are owned directly, indirectly, or constructively by the taxpayer, or any person related to the taxpayer, during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year.  For purposes of this subsection, the constructive ownership rules of section318(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified by section856(d) (5) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall apply in determining the ownership of stock, assets, or net profits of any person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_9an">
            <num>(9an)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(9an)  For purposes of s.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 46., “rental expenses” means the gross amounts that would otherwise be deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income for the use of, or the right to use, real property and tangible personal property in connection with real property, including services furnished or rendered in connection with such property, regardless of how reported for financial accounting purposes and regardless of how computed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_9c">
            <num>(9c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(9c)  “Sign” means write one’s signature or, if the department prescribes another method of authenticating, use that other method.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(10)  “Small business stock” means an equity security, sold before January 1, 2014, that the taxpayer has held for at least 5 years and that is issued by a corporation that, on the December 31 before acquisition by the taxpayer, or, for a corporation which was incorporated during the calendar year in which the stock is issued, as of the date of the acquisition of the stock, fulfills all of the following requirements and so certifies to the taxpayer upon acquisitions:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_10g">
            <num>(10g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(10g)  For purposes of s.71.04 (7) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “state” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States, unless the context requires that “state” means only the state of Wisconsin.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(11)  “Taxable income” when not preceded by the word “federal” means Wisconsin taxable income unless otherwise defined or the context plainly requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(12)  “Taxable year” means the taxable period upon the basis of which the taxable income of the taxpayer is computed for federal income tax purposes.  The taxable year of a taxpayer who keeps his or her accounting records on the basis of a 52-53 week period ends on the last day of the month closest to the end of the 52-53 week period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(13)  “Wisconsin adjusted gross income” means federal adjusted gross income, with the modifications prescribed in s.71.05 (6)to(12),(19),(20),(24),(25),(25m), and(26).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(14)  “Wisconsin net operating loss” of persons other than corporations means “federal net operating loss” adjusted as prescribed in s.71.05 (6) (a)and(b),(7)to(12)and(19)to(21), except s.71.05 (6) (b) 9., except that no deductions allowable on schedule A for federal income tax purposes are allowable.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(16)  “Wisconsin taxable income” of natural persons means Wisconsin adjusted gross income less the Wisconsin standard deduction, less the personal exemption described under s.71.05 (23), with losses, depreciation, recapture of benefits, offsets, depletion, deductions, penalties, expenses and other negative income items determined according to the manner that income is or would be allocated, except that the negative income items on individual or separate returns for net rents and other net returns which are marital property attributable to the investment, rental, licensing or other use of nonmarital property shall be allocated to the owner of the property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.02(1)  For the purpose of raising revenue for the state and the counties, cities, villages and towns, there shall be assessed, levied, collected and paid a tax on all net incomes of individuals and fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds subject to the tax under s.71.23 (2), by every natural person residing within the state or by his or her personal representative in case of death, and trusts resident within the state; by every nonresident natural person and trust of this state, upon such income as is derived from property located or business transacted within the state including, but not limited by enumeration, income derived from a limited partner’s distributive share of partnership income, income derived from a limited liability company member’s distributive share of limited liability company income, income derived from a covenant not to compete to the extent that the covenant was based on a Wisconsin-based activity, the state lottery under ch.565, any multijurisdictional lottery under ch.565if the winning lottery ticket or lottery share was purchased from a retailer, as defined in s.565.01 (6), located in this state or from the department, winnings from a casino or bingo hall that is located in this state and that is operated by a Native American tribe or band and pari-mutuel wager winnings or purses under ch.562, and also by every nonresident natural person upon such income as is derived from the performance of personal services within the state, except as exempted under s.71.05 (1)to(3).  Every natural person domiciled in the state shall be deemed to be residing within the state for the purposes of determining liability for income taxes and surtaxes.  A single-owner entity that is disregarded as a separate entity under section7701of the Internal Revenue Code is disregarded as a separate entity under this chapter, and its owner is subject to the tax on the entity’s income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.02(2)  In determining whether or not an individual resides within this state for purposes of this section, the following are not relevant:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.02(3)  This section shall not be construed to prevent or affect the correction of errors or omissions in the assessments of income for former years under s.71.74 (1)and(2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(1)  Definition. In this section, “gross income” means all income, from whatever source derived and in whatever form realized, whether in money, property or services, which is not exempt from Wisconsin income taxes.  “Gross income” includes, but is not limited to, the following items:  compensation for services, including salaries, wages and fees, commissions and similar items; gross income derived from business; interest; rents; royalties; dividends; alimony and separate maintenance payments; annuities; income from life insurance and endowment contracts; pensions; income from discharge of indebtedness; distributive shares of partnership gross income except distributive shares of the income of publicly traded partnerships treated as corporations under s.71.22 (1k); distributive shares of limited liability company gross income except distributive shares of the income of limited liability companies treated as corporations under s.71.22 (1k); income in respect of a decedent; and income from an interest in an estate or trust.  “Gross income” from a business or farm consists of the total gross receipts without reduction for cost of goods sold, expenses or any other amounts.  The gross rental amounts received from rental properties are included in gross income without reduction for expenses or any other amounts.  “Gross income” from the sale of securities, property or other assets consists of the gross selling price without reduction for the cost of the assets, expenses of sale or any other amounts.  “Gross income” from an annuity, retirement plan or profit sharing plan consists of the gross amount received without reduction for the employee’s contribution to the annuity or plan.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(2)  Persons required to file; other requirements. The following shall report in accordance with this section:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(3)  Fractional part of year. If a natural person or fiduciary files a federal income tax return for a fractional part of the year, the person shall file a Wisconsin income tax return for that fractional year.  That person shall compute and report income on the basis of the period for which that return is filed, and that fractional year shall constitute a taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(4)  Election to have department compute tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(5)  Copy of federal return. To the extent necessary for the administration of the tax imposed by this chapter, when required under rules prescribed or orders issued by the department or upon the written request of the department, natural persons and fiduciaries subject to this chapter shall file with the department a true and complete copy of their federal income tax return and any other return or statement filed with, or made to, or any document received from, the internal revenue service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-02__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(6)  Time return required.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-03">
          <num>71.03</num>
          <heading>Imposition of tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_9an">
            <num>(9an)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(9an)  For purposes of s.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 46., “rental expenses” means the gross amounts that would otherwise be deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income for the use of, or the right to use, real property and tangible personal property in connection with real property, including services furnished or rendered in connection with such property, regardless of how reported for financial accounting purposes and regardless of how computed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_9c">
            <num>(9c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(9c)  “Sign” means write one’s signature or, if the department prescribes another method of authenticating, use that other method.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(10)  “Small business stock” means an equity security, sold before January 1, 2014, that the taxpayer has held for at least 5 years and that is issued by a corporation that, on the December 31 before acquisition by the taxpayer, or, for a corporation which was incorporated during the calendar year in which the stock is issued, as of the date of the acquisition of the stock, fulfills all of the following requirements and so certifies to the taxpayer upon acquisitions:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_10g">
            <num>(10g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(10g)  For purposes of s.71.04 (7) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “state” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States, unless the context requires that “state” means only the state of Wisconsin.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(11)  “Taxable income” when not preceded by the word “federal” means Wisconsin taxable income unless otherwise defined or the context plainly requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(12)  “Taxable year” means the taxable period upon the basis of which the taxable income of the taxpayer is computed for federal income tax purposes.  The taxable year of a taxpayer who keeps his or her accounting records on the basis of a 52-53 week period ends on the last day of the month closest to the end of the 52-53 week period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(13)  “Wisconsin adjusted gross income” means federal adjusted gross income, with the modifications prescribed in s.71.05 (6)to(12),(19),(20),(24),(25),(25m), and(26).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(14)  “Wisconsin net operating loss” of persons other than corporations means “federal net operating loss” adjusted as prescribed in s.71.05 (6) (a)and(b),(7)to(12)and(19)to(21), except s.71.05 (6) (b) 9., except that no deductions allowable on schedule A for federal income tax purposes are allowable.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.01(16)  “Wisconsin taxable income” of natural persons means Wisconsin adjusted gross income less the Wisconsin standard deduction, less the personal exemption described under s.71.05 (23), with losses, depreciation, recapture of benefits, offsets, depletion, deductions, penalties, expenses and other negative income items determined according to the manner that income is or would be allocated, except that the negative income items on individual or separate returns for net rents and other net returns which are marital property attributable to the investment, rental, licensing or other use of nonmarital property shall be allocated to the owner of the property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.02(1)  For the purpose of raising revenue for the state and the counties, cities, villages and towns, there shall be assessed, levied, collected and paid a tax on all net incomes of individuals and fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds subject to the tax under s.71.23 (2), by every natural person residing within the state or by his or her personal representative in case of death, and trusts resident within the state; by every nonresident natural person and trust of this state, upon such income as is derived from property located or business transacted within the state including, but not limited by enumeration, income derived from a limited partner’s distributive share of partnership income, income derived from a limited liability company member’s distributive share of limited liability company income, income derived from a covenant not to compete to the extent that the covenant was based on a Wisconsin-based activity, the state lottery under ch.565, any multijurisdictional lottery under ch.565if the winning lottery ticket or lottery share was purchased from a retailer, as defined in s.565.01 (6), located in this state or from the department, winnings from a casino or bingo hall that is located in this state and that is operated by a Native American tribe or band and pari-mutuel wager winnings or purses under ch.562, and also by every nonresident natural person upon such income as is derived from the performance of personal services within the state, except as exempted under s.71.05 (1)to(3).  Every natural person domiciled in the state shall be deemed to be residing within the state for the purposes of determining liability for income taxes and surtaxes.  A single-owner entity that is disregarded as a separate entity under section7701of the Internal Revenue Code is disregarded as a separate entity under this chapter, and its owner is subject to the tax on the entity’s income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.02(2)  In determining whether or not an individual resides within this state for purposes of this section, the following are not relevant:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.02(3)  This section shall not be construed to prevent or affect the correction of errors or omissions in the assessments of income for former years under s.71.74 (1)and(2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(1)  Definition. In this section, “gross income” means all income, from whatever source derived and in whatever form realized, whether in money, property or services, which is not exempt from Wisconsin income taxes.  “Gross income” includes, but is not limited to, the following items:  compensation for services, including salaries, wages and fees, commissions and similar items; gross income derived from business; interest; rents; royalties; dividends; alimony and separate maintenance payments; annuities; income from life insurance and endowment contracts; pensions; income from discharge of indebtedness; distributive shares of partnership gross income except distributive shares of the income of publicly traded partnerships treated as corporations under s.71.22 (1k); distributive shares of limited liability company gross income except distributive shares of the income of limited liability companies treated as corporations under s.71.22 (1k); income in respect of a decedent; and income from an interest in an estate or trust.  “Gross income” from a business or farm consists of the total gross receipts without reduction for cost of goods sold, expenses or any other amounts.  The gross rental amounts received from rental properties are included in gross income without reduction for expenses or any other amounts.  “Gross income” from the sale of securities, property or other assets consists of the gross selling price without reduction for the cost of the assets, expenses of sale or any other amounts.  “Gross income” from an annuity, retirement plan or profit sharing plan consists of the gross amount received without reduction for the employee’s contribution to the annuity or plan.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(2)  Persons required to file; other requirements. The following shall report in accordance with this section:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(3)  Fractional part of year. If a natural person or fiduciary files a federal income tax return for a fractional part of the year, the person shall file a Wisconsin income tax return for that fractional year.  That person shall compute and report income on the basis of the period for which that return is filed, and that fractional year shall constitute a taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(4)  Election to have department compute tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(5)  Copy of federal return. To the extent necessary for the administration of the tax imposed by this chapter, when required under rules prescribed or orders issued by the department or upon the written request of the department, natural persons and fiduciaries subject to this chapter shall file with the department a true and complete copy of their federal income tax return and any other return or statement filed with, or made to, or any document received from, the internal revenue service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(6)  Time return required.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_6m">
            <num>(6m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(6m)  Time to file claims; no return required. A claim for a credit under [s. 71.07 (3m) or] subch.VIIIorIXthat is filed by a natural person who is not required to file a report under sub.(2) (a)shall be filed on a calendar year basis in conformity with the filing requirements in subs.(6)and(7).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(7)  Extension of time to file. Returns of natural persons and fiduciaries that require a statement of amounts or information contained or entered on a corresponding return under the internal revenue code shall be filed within the time fixed under that code for filing of the corresponding federal return.  Any extension of time granted by law or by the internal revenue service for the filing of that corresponding federal return extends the time for filing under this chapter if a copy of the taxpayer’s application to the internal revenue service requesting the extension is filed with the return under this chapter or if a copy of any request for an extension required by the internal revenue service is filed with the return under this chapter or at an earlier date that the department prescribes by rule and if the taxpayer pays the Wisconsin tax in the manner applicable to federal income taxes under the internal revenue code.  Taxes payable upon the filing of the return do not become delinquent during the period of an extension but are subject to interest at the rate of 12 percent per year during such period except as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-03__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(8)  Payment of tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-04">
          <num>71.04</num>
          <heading>Situs of income; allocation and apportionment</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(3)  Fractional part of year. If a natural person or fiduciary files a federal income tax return for a fractional part of the year, the person shall file a Wisconsin income tax return for that fractional year.  That person shall compute and report income on the basis of the period for which that return is filed, and that fractional year shall constitute a taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(4)  Election to have department compute tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(5)  Copy of federal return. To the extent necessary for the administration of the tax imposed by this chapter, when required under rules prescribed or orders issued by the department or upon the written request of the department, natural persons and fiduciaries subject to this chapter shall file with the department a true and complete copy of their federal income tax return and any other return or statement filed with, or made to, or any document received from, the internal revenue service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(6)  Time return required.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_6m">
            <num>(6m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(6m)  Time to file claims; no return required. A claim for a credit under [s. 71.07 (3m) or] subch.VIIIorIXthat is filed by a natural person who is not required to file a report under sub.(2) (a)shall be filed on a calendar year basis in conformity with the filing requirements in subs.(6)and(7).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(7)  Extension of time to file. Returns of natural persons and fiduciaries that require a statement of amounts or information contained or entered on a corresponding return under the internal revenue code shall be filed within the time fixed under that code for filing of the corresponding federal return.  Any extension of time granted by law or by the internal revenue service for the filing of that corresponding federal return extends the time for filing under this chapter if a copy of the taxpayer’s application to the internal revenue service requesting the extension is filed with the return under this chapter or if a copy of any request for an extension required by the internal revenue service is filed with the return under this chapter or at an earlier date that the department prescribes by rule and if the taxpayer pays the Wisconsin tax in the manner applicable to federal income taxes under the internal revenue code.  Taxes payable upon the filing of the return do not become delinquent during the period of an extension but are subject to interest at the rate of 12 percent per year during such period except as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.03(8)  Payment of tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(1)  Situs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(2)  Part-year resident liability determination. Liability to taxation for income which follows the residence of the recipient, in the case of persons other than corporations, who move into or out of the state within the year, shall be determined for such year on the basis of the income received (or accrued, if on the accrual basis) during the portion of the year that any such person was a resident of Wisconsin.  The net income of such person assignable to the state for such year shall be used in determining the income subject to assessment under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(3)  Partners and limited liability company members.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(4)  Nonresident allocation and apportionment formula. Nonresident individuals and nonresident estates and trusts engaged in business within and without the state shall be taxed only on such income as is derived from business transacted and property located within the state.  The amount of such income attributable to Wisconsin may be determined by an allocation and separate accounting thereof, when the business of such nonresident individual or nonresident estate or trust within the state is not an integral part of a unitary business, but the department of revenue may permit an allocation and separate accounting in any case in which it is satisfied that the use of such method will properly reflect the income taxable by this state.  In all cases in which allocation and separate accounting is not permissible, the determination shall be made in the following manner:  for all businesses except air carriers, financial organizations, telecommunications companies, pipeline companies, public utilities, railroads, and car line companies there shall first be deducted from the total net income of the taxpayer the part thereof (less related expenses, if any) that follows the situs of the property or the residence of the recipient.  The remaining net income shall be apportioned to this state by use of the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(4m)  Apportionment formula computation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(5)  Property factor. For purposes of sub.(4)and for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2008:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(6)  Payroll factor. For purposes of sub.(4)and for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2008:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-04__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(7)  Sales factor. For purposes of sub.(4):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-05">
          <num>71.05</num>
          <heading>Income computation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(8)  Railroads, financial organizations and public utilities.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(9)  Nonresident income from multistate tax-option corporation. Nonresident individuals and nonresident estates and trusts deriving income from a tax-option corporation which is engaged in business within and without this state shall be taxed only on the income of the corporation derived from business transacted and property located in this state and losses and other items of the corporation deductible by such shareholders shall be limited to their proportionate share of the Wisconsin loss or other item, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.  For purposes of this subsection, all intangible income of tax-option corporations passed through to shareholders is business income that follows the situs of the business, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(10)  Department may waive factor. Where, in the case of any nonresident individual or nonresident estate or trust engaged in business in and outside of this state and required to apportion its income as provided in this section, it shall be shown to the satisfaction of the department of revenue that the use of any one of the 3 factors provided under sub.(4)gives an unreasonable or inequitable final average ratio because of the fact that such nonresident individual or nonresident estate or trust does not employ, to any appreciable extent in its trade or business in producing the income taxed, the factors made use of in obtaining such ratio, this factor may, with the approval of the department of revenue, be omitted in obtaining the final average ratio which is to be applied to the remaining net income.  This subsection does not apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2007.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.04(11)  Department may apportion by rule. If the income of any such nonresident individual or nonresident estate or trust properly assignable to the state of Wisconsin cannot be ascertained with reasonable certainty by the methods under this section, then the same shall be apportioned and allocated under such rules as the department of revenue may prescribe.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.05(1)  Exempt and excludable income. There shall be exempt from taxation under this subchapter the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.05(2)  Nonresident reciprocity. All payments received by natural persons domiciled outside Wisconsin who derive income from the performance of personal services in Wisconsin shall be excluded from Wisconsin gross income to the extent that it is subjected to an income tax imposed by the state of domicile; provided that the law of the state of domicile allows a similar exclusion of income from personal services earned in such state by natural persons domiciled in Wisconsin, or a credit against the tax imposed by such state on such income equal to the Wisconsin tax on such income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.05(3)  Menominee Indian tribe; distribution of assets. No distribution of assets from the United States to the members of the Menominee Indian tribe as defined in s.49.385or their lawful distributees, or to any corporation, or organization, created by the tribe or at its direction pursuant to section 8, P.L.83-399, as amended, and no issuance of stocks, bonds, certificates of indebtedness, voting trust certificates or other securities by any such corporation or organization, or voting trust, to such members of the tribe or their lawful distributees shall be subject to income taxes under this chapter; provided, that so much of any cash distribution made under said P.L.83-399as consists of a share of any interest earned on funds deposited in the treasury of the United States pursuant to the supplemental appropriation act, 1952, (65 Stat. 736, 754) shall not by virtue of this subsection be exempt from the individual income tax of this state in the hands of the recipients for the year in which paid.  For the purpose of ascertaining the gain or loss resulting from the sale or other disposition of such assets and stocks, bonds, certificates of indebtedness and other securities under this chapter, the fair market value of such property, on termination date as defined in s.70.057 (1), 1967 stats., shall be the basis for determining the amount of such gain or loss.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.05(5)  Fractional year. When an income tax return is required to be filed for a fractional part of a year under s.71.03 (3), the Wisconsin taxable income shall be placed on an annual basis using the method applicable for federal income taxes under section443(b) (1) of the internal revenue code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-05__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.05(6)  Modifications and transitional adjustments. Some of the modifications referred to in s.71.01 (13)and(14)are:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-06">
          <num>71.06</num>
          <heading>Rates of taxation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_26">
            <num>(26)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.05(26)  Income tax deferral; qualified Wisconsin business.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(1)  Fiduciaries, single individuals and heads of households; 1986 to 1997. The tax to be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable incomes of all fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds, and single individuals for taxable years beginning on or after August 1, 1986, and before January 1, 1994, and upon the taxable incomes of all fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds, and single individuals and heads of households for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1993, and before January 1, 1998, shall be computed at the following rates:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(1m)  Fiduciaries, single individuals and heads of households; 1997 to 1999. The tax to be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable incomes of all fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds, and single individuals and heads of households shall be computed at the following rates for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1997, and before January 1, 2000:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_1n">
            <num>(1n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(1n)  Fiduciaries, single individuals and heads of households; 2000. The tax to be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable incomes of all fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds, and single individuals and heads of households shall be computed at the following rates for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1999, and before January 1, 2001:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_1p">
            <num>(1p)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(1p)  Fiduciaries, single individuals and heads of households; 2001 to 2012. The tax to be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable incomes of all fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds, and single individuals and heads of households shall be computed at the following rates for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2000, and before January 1, 2013:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_1q">
            <num>(1q)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(1q)  Fiduciaries, single individuals, and heads of households; 2012 to 2024. The tax to be assessed, levied, and collected upon the taxable incomes of all fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds, and single individuals and heads of households shall be computed at the following rates for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2012, and before January 1, 2025:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_1r">
            <num>(1r)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(1r)  Fiduciaries, single individuals, and heads of household; after 2024. The tax to be assessed, levied, and collected upon the taxable incomes of all fiduciaries, except fiduciaries of nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve funds, and single individuals and heads of households shall be computed at the following rates for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2024:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(2)  Married persons. The tax to be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable incomes of all married persons shall be computed at the following rates:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-07">
          <num>71.07</num>
          <heading>Credits</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_2e">
            <num>(2e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(2e)  Bracket indexing.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_2m">
            <num>(2m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(2m)  Rate changes. If a rate under sub.(1r)or(2) (k)or(L)changes during a taxable year, the taxpayer shall compute the tax for that taxable year by the methods applicable to the federal income tax under section15of the Internal Revenue Code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_2s">
            <num>(2s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(2s)  Nonresidents and part-year residents.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.06(3)  Tax table. The secretary of revenue shall prepare a table from which the tax in effect on taxable personal income shall be determined.  Such table shall be published in the department’s appropriate instructional booklets.  The form and the tax computations of the table shall be substantially as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(1)  Claim of right credit. Any natural person may credit against taxes otherwise due under this chapter the decrease in tax under this chapter for the prior taxable year that would be attributable to subtracting income taxed for that year under the claim of right doctrine but repaid, as calculated under section1341of the internal revenue code, if the income repaid is greater than $3,000 and the amount is not subtracted in computing Wisconsin adjusted gross income or used in computing the credit under sub.(5) (a).  If the allowable amount of the claim exceeds the claimant’s taxes due under this chapter the amount of the claim not used to offset those taxes shall be certified to the department of administration for payment to the claimant by check, share draft or other draft drawn on the general fund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_2dm">
            <num>(2dm)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(2dm)  Development zone capital investment credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_2dx">
            <num>(2dx)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(2dx)  Development zones credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_2dy">
            <num>(2dy)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(2dy)  Economic development tax credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(3)  Farmland preservation credit. The farmland preservation credit under subch.IXmay be claimed against taxes otherwise due.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-07__subsec_3g">
            <num>(3g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(3g)  Technology zones credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-08">
          <num>71.08</num>
          <heading>Minimum tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(10)  Employee college savings account contribution credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(11)  Qualifying transportation services credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(1)  Imposition. If the tax imposed on a natural person, married couple filing jointly, trust, or estate under s.71.02, not considering the credits under ss.71.07 (1),(2dx),(2dy),(3m),(3n),(3q),(3s),(3t),(3w),(3wm),(3y),(4k),(5b),(5d),(5i),(5j),(5n),(6),(6e),(8b),(9e),(9m), and(9r),71.28 (1dx),(1dy),(2m),(3),(3n),(3t),(3w),(3wm), and(3y),71.47 (1dx),(1dy),(2m),(3),(3n),(3t),(3w), and(3y),71.57to71.61, and71.613and subch.VIIIand payments to other states under s.71.07 (7), is less than the tax under this section, there is imposed on that natural person, married couple filing jointly, trust or estate, instead of the tax under s.71.02, an alternative minimum tax computed as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(2)  Joint liability. If the requirements under sub.(1)are applicable and the spouses file a joint income tax return, they shall file a joint minimum tax return and are jointly and severally liable for the tax imposed under sub.(1)and for the interest, penalties, fees, additions to tax and additional assessments with respect to the tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(3)  Administration. The department of revenue shall have full power to impose, enforce and collect the minimum tax provided in this section and may take any action, conduct any proceeding and in all respects proceed as it is authorized in respect to income taxes imposed in this chapter.  The income tax provisions in this chapter relating to assessments, refunds, appeals, collection, interest and penalties shall apply to the minimum tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(4)  Tax benefit rule. The department of revenue shall promulgate rules to provide that the amount under sub.(1)may be reduced to prevent the inclusion of any amounts, except the federal standard deductions, itemized deductions and personal exemptions, that do not reflect a benefit in respect to the tax imposed under s.71.02.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(5)  Sunset. This section does not apply to taxable years beginning after December 31.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(1)  Definitions. In this section:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(2)  Who shall pay. Every individual, estate and trust deriving income subject to taxation under this chapter, other than wages as defined in s.71.63 (6)upon which taxes are withheld by the individual’s employer under subch.X, shall pay estimated income tax and the surcharge under s.77.93.  This section does not apply to any person on active duty with the U.S. armed forces while stationed outside the continental United States.  This section does not apply to any taxable year ending before the date 2 years after the date of a decedent’s death with respect to the estate of such decedent or any trust all of which is treated under subpart E of part I of subchapter J of chapter 1 of the internal revenue code as owned by the decedent and to which the residue of the decedent’s estate will pass under his or her will.  This section does not apply to any trust that is subject to tax under this chapter on unrelated business taxable income as defined under section512of the internal revenue code.  Those trusts are subject to estimated tax payments under s.71.29.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(3)  Farmers or fishers. Payments of estimated income tax required by sub.(2)from farmers or fishers may be made at any time on or before the 15th day of the first month of the succeeding taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(4)  Farmers or fishers exception. Except as provided in sub.(1) (am), if on or before the first day of the 3rd month of the succeeding taxable year a farmer or a fisher files a return for the taxable year, for which estimated taxes were required on or before the 15th day of the first month of the succeeding taxable year under sub.(3), and pays in full the amount computed on the return as payable, then that payment satisfies any required estimated tax installments.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(5)  Amount. The amount of the estimated income tax shall be the total estimated tax, including surtaxes, if any, reduced by the amount, if any, the individual, estate or trust determines will be withheld from wages pursuant to subch.X.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(7)  Refund carry-forward. If the taxpayer claims a refund on any tax return and, concurrent with or subsequent to the filing of the return upon which such refund is claimed, is required to pay an estimated tax, and at the time of paying that tax the refund has not been paid, he or she may deduct the amount of such refund from the first installment of estimated taxes, and any excess from the succeeding installments.  If a refund is paid after the due date of the last installment, its receipt shall be reflected on the income tax return covering the year.  If the refund is disallowed in whole or in part after the due date of the last installment, that disallowance must be reflected on the income tax return covering the year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(8)  Prepayments. Any installment of the estimated tax under this section may be paid prior to the date prescribed for its payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(9)  Short year. Application of this section to taxable years of less than 12 full months shall be made pursuant to rules of the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(10)  Overpayment. When the amount of an installment payment of estimated tax exceeds the amount determined to be the correct amount of such installment payment, the overpayment shall be credited against the unpaid installment, if any.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(11)  Exceptions to interest. No interest is required under s.71.84 (1)if any of the following conditions apply:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(12)  Installment due dates. Taxpayers shall make estimated payments in 4 installments, on or before the 15th day of each of the following months:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(13)  Installment amounts.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(14)  Exception to final installment. If a taxpayer files a return for a calendar year on or before January 31 of the succeeding calendar year (or if a taxpayer on a fiscal year basis files a return on or before the last day of the first month immediately succeeding the close of such fiscal year) and pays in full at the time of such filing the amount computed on the return as payable, then, if estimated taxes are not required to be paid on or before the 15th day of the 9th month of the taxable year but are required to be paid on or before January 15 of the succeeding taxable year (or the date corresponding thereto in the case of a fiscal year), such return shall be considered as such payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(15)  Exemption from withholding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(16)  Joint payments. Married persons may jointly pay estimated taxes unless either spouse is a nonresident alien or the spouses have different taxable years.  If they do pay jointly, the provisions under this section applicable to individuals are applicable to the married persons jointly.  If a married person files a separate return for a taxable year for which a joint payment was made, the payments may be allocated between themselves as they choose, but if they do not agree on an allocation the department of revenue shall allocate the payments to each spouse on the basis of the ratio of taxes shown on their separate returns or pursuant to default assessment under s.71.74 (3).  If either spouse pays separately, no part of the payment may be allocated to the other spouse.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-08__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(1)  Allocation of gross income, deductions, credits between 2 or more businesses. In any case of 2 or more organizations, trades or businesses (whether or not incorporated, whether or not organized in the United States, whether or not affiliated, and whether or not unitary) owned or controlled directly or indirectly by the same interests, the secretary or the secretary’s delegate may distribute, apportion or allocate gross income, deductions, credits or allowances between or among such organizations, trades or businesses, if the secretary determines that such distribution, apportionment or allocation is necessary in order to prevent evasion of taxes or clearly to reflect the income of any of such organizations, trades or businesses.  The authority granted under this subsection is in addition to, and not a limitation of or dependent on, the provisions of ss.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 45.,71.26 (2) (a) 7.and8.,71.34 (1k) (j)and(k),71.45 (2) (a) 16.and17., and71.80 (23).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-09">
          <num>71.09</num>
          <heading>Minimum tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.07(11)  Qualifying transportation services credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(1)  Imposition. If the tax imposed on a natural person, married couple filing jointly, trust, or estate under s.71.02, not considering the credits under ss.71.07 (1),(2dx),(2dy),(3m),(3n),(3q),(3s),(3t),(3w),(3wm),(3y),(4k),(5b),(5d),(5i),(5j),(5n),(6),(6e),(8b),(9e),(9m), and(9r),71.28 (1dx),(1dy),(2m),(3),(3n),(3t),(3w),(3wm), and(3y),71.47 (1dx),(1dy),(2m),(3),(3n),(3t),(3w), and(3y),71.57to71.61, and71.613and subch.VIIIand payments to other states under s.71.07 (7), is less than the tax under this section, there is imposed on that natural person, married couple filing jointly, trust or estate, instead of the tax under s.71.02, an alternative minimum tax computed as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(2)  Joint liability. If the requirements under sub.(1)are applicable and the spouses file a joint income tax return, they shall file a joint minimum tax return and are jointly and severally liable for the tax imposed under sub.(1)and for the interest, penalties, fees, additions to tax and additional assessments with respect to the tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(3)  Administration. The department of revenue shall have full power to impose, enforce and collect the minimum tax provided in this section and may take any action, conduct any proceeding and in all respects proceed as it is authorized in respect to income taxes imposed in this chapter.  The income tax provisions in this chapter relating to assessments, refunds, appeals, collection, interest and penalties shall apply to the minimum tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(4)  Tax benefit rule. The department of revenue shall promulgate rules to provide that the amount under sub.(1)may be reduced to prevent the inclusion of any amounts, except the federal standard deductions, itemized deductions and personal exemptions, that do not reflect a benefit in respect to the tax imposed under s.71.02.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.08(5)  Sunset. This section does not apply to taxable years beginning after December 31.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(1)  Definitions. In this section:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(2)  Who shall pay. Every individual, estate and trust deriving income subject to taxation under this chapter, other than wages as defined in s.71.63 (6)upon which taxes are withheld by the individual’s employer under subch.X, shall pay estimated income tax and the surcharge under s.77.93.  This section does not apply to any person on active duty with the U.S. armed forces while stationed outside the continental United States.  This section does not apply to any taxable year ending before the date 2 years after the date of a decedent’s death with respect to the estate of such decedent or any trust all of which is treated under subpart E of part I of subchapter J of chapter 1 of the internal revenue code as owned by the decedent and to which the residue of the decedent’s estate will pass under his or her will.  This section does not apply to any trust that is subject to tax under this chapter on unrelated business taxable income as defined under section512of the internal revenue code.  Those trusts are subject to estimated tax payments under s.71.29.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(3)  Farmers or fishers. Payments of estimated income tax required by sub.(2)from farmers or fishers may be made at any time on or before the 15th day of the first month of the succeeding taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(4)  Farmers or fishers exception. Except as provided in sub.(1) (am), if on or before the first day of the 3rd month of the succeeding taxable year a farmer or a fisher files a return for the taxable year, for which estimated taxes were required on or before the 15th day of the first month of the succeeding taxable year under sub.(3), and pays in full the amount computed on the return as payable, then that payment satisfies any required estimated tax installments.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(5)  Amount. The amount of the estimated income tax shall be the total estimated tax, including surtaxes, if any, reduced by the amount, if any, the individual, estate or trust determines will be withheld from wages pursuant to subch.X.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(7)  Refund carry-forward. If the taxpayer claims a refund on any tax return and, concurrent with or subsequent to the filing of the return upon which such refund is claimed, is required to pay an estimated tax, and at the time of paying that tax the refund has not been paid, he or she may deduct the amount of such refund from the first installment of estimated taxes, and any excess from the succeeding installments.  If a refund is paid after the due date of the last installment, its receipt shall be reflected on the income tax return covering the year.  If the refund is disallowed in whole or in part after the due date of the last installment, that disallowance must be reflected on the income tax return covering the year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(8)  Prepayments. Any installment of the estimated tax under this section may be paid prior to the date prescribed for its payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(9)  Short year. Application of this section to taxable years of less than 12 full months shall be made pursuant to rules of the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(10)  Overpayment. When the amount of an installment payment of estimated tax exceeds the amount determined to be the correct amount of such installment payment, the overpayment shall be credited against the unpaid installment, if any.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(11)  Exceptions to interest. No interest is required under s.71.84 (1)if any of the following conditions apply:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(12)  Installment due dates. Taxpayers shall make estimated payments in 4 installments, on or before the 15th day of each of the following months:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(13)  Installment amounts.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(14)  Exception to final installment. If a taxpayer files a return for a calendar year on or before January 31 of the succeeding calendar year (or if a taxpayer on a fiscal year basis files a return on or before the last day of the first month immediately succeeding the close of such fiscal year) and pays in full at the time of such filing the amount computed on the return as payable, then, if estimated taxes are not required to be paid on or before the 15th day of the 9th month of the taxable year but are required to be paid on or before January 15 of the succeeding taxable year (or the date corresponding thereto in the case of a fiscal year), such return shall be considered as such payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(15)  Exemption from withholding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(16)  Joint payments. Married persons may jointly pay estimated taxes unless either spouse is a nonresident alien or the spouses have different taxable years.  If they do pay jointly, the provisions under this section applicable to individuals are applicable to the married persons jointly.  If a married person files a separate return for a taxable year for which a joint payment was made, the payments may be allocated between themselves as they choose, but if they do not agree on an allocation the department of revenue shall allocate the payments to each spouse on the basis of the ratio of taxes shown on their separate returns or pursuant to default assessment under s.71.74 (3).  If either spouse pays separately, no part of the payment may be allocated to the other spouse.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(1)  Allocation of gross income, deductions, credits between 2 or more businesses. In any case of 2 or more organizations, trades or businesses (whether or not incorporated, whether or not organized in the United States, whether or not affiliated, and whether or not unitary) owned or controlled directly or indirectly by the same interests, the secretary or the secretary’s delegate may distribute, apportion or allocate gross income, deductions, credits or allowances between or among such organizations, trades or businesses, if the secretary determines that such distribution, apportionment or allocation is necessary in order to prevent evasion of taxes or clearly to reflect the income of any of such organizations, trades or businesses.  The authority granted under this subsection is in addition to, and not a limitation of or dependent on, the provisions of ss.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 45.,71.26 (2) (a) 7.and8.,71.34 (1k) (j)and(k),71.45 (2) (a) 16.and17., and71.80 (23).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(1m)  Transactions without economic substance.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(2)  Assessment of income distributable to a nonresident beneficiary. The income of a trust distributable or distributed to a nonresident beneficiary shall be assessed as the income of other nonresidents is assessed.  No personal exemptions shall be allowed in assessing the income of such nonresident beneficiary unless that person makes a complete return under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-09__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(4)  Computation order. Notwithstanding any other provisions in this chapter, all persons other than corporations computing liability for the tax under s.71.02shall make computations in the following order:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-10">
          <num>71.10</num>
          <heading>General provisions</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(10)  Overpayment. When the amount of an installment payment of estimated tax exceeds the amount determined to be the correct amount of such installment payment, the overpayment shall be credited against the unpaid installment, if any.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(11)  Exceptions to interest. No interest is required under s.71.84 (1)if any of the following conditions apply:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(12)  Installment due dates. Taxpayers shall make estimated payments in 4 installments, on or before the 15th day of each of the following months:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(13)  Installment amounts.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(14)  Exception to final installment. If a taxpayer files a return for a calendar year on or before January 31 of the succeeding calendar year (or if a taxpayer on a fiscal year basis files a return on or before the last day of the first month immediately succeeding the close of such fiscal year) and pays in full at the time of such filing the amount computed on the return as payable, then, if estimated taxes are not required to be paid on or before the 15th day of the 9th month of the taxable year but are required to be paid on or before January 15 of the succeeding taxable year (or the date corresponding thereto in the case of a fiscal year), such return shall be considered as such payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(15)  Exemption from withholding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.09(16)  Joint payments. Married persons may jointly pay estimated taxes unless either spouse is a nonresident alien or the spouses have different taxable years.  If they do pay jointly, the provisions under this section applicable to individuals are applicable to the married persons jointly.  If a married person files a separate return for a taxable year for which a joint payment was made, the payments may be allocated between themselves as they choose, but if they do not agree on an allocation the department of revenue shall allocate the payments to each spouse on the basis of the ratio of taxes shown on their separate returns or pursuant to default assessment under s.71.74 (3).  If either spouse pays separately, no part of the payment may be allocated to the other spouse.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(1)  Allocation of gross income, deductions, credits between 2 or more businesses. In any case of 2 or more organizations, trades or businesses (whether or not incorporated, whether or not organized in the United States, whether or not affiliated, and whether or not unitary) owned or controlled directly or indirectly by the same interests, the secretary or the secretary’s delegate may distribute, apportion or allocate gross income, deductions, credits or allowances between or among such organizations, trades or businesses, if the secretary determines that such distribution, apportionment or allocation is necessary in order to prevent evasion of taxes or clearly to reflect the income of any of such organizations, trades or businesses.  The authority granted under this subsection is in addition to, and not a limitation of or dependent on, the provisions of ss.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 45.,71.26 (2) (a) 7.and8.,71.34 (1k) (j)and(k),71.45 (2) (a) 16.and17., and71.80 (23).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(1m)  Transactions without economic substance.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(2)  Assessment of income distributable to a nonresident beneficiary. The income of a trust distributable or distributed to a nonresident beneficiary shall be assessed as the income of other nonresidents is assessed.  No personal exemptions shall be allowed in assessing the income of such nonresident beneficiary unless that person makes a complete return under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(4)  Computation order. Notwithstanding any other provisions in this chapter, all persons other than corporations computing liability for the tax under s.71.02shall make computations in the following order:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-10__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.10(5)  Endangered resources.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-21">
          <num>71.21</num>
          <heading>Allocation of modifications</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.16(1)  A modification or portion thereof which relates to an item of income, gain, loss or deduction which affects the computation of the federal distributable net income of the estate or trust for the current year shall be apportioned among and taken into account by the fiduciary and the beneficiary or beneficiaries in the same proportion that the item to which it relates is considered as distributed among them for federal income tax purposes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.16(2)  Any remaining modifications or portions thereof shall be taken into account by the fiduciary.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.16(3)  If an additional assessment is made against the fiduciary or any beneficiary as a result of correction of an erroneous allocation of the modifications applicable to the income of an estate or trust, any overpayment resulting from consistent application of such correction to all other taxpayers interested in such estate or trust shall be refunded notwithstanding any rule of law which would otherwise bar such refund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.17(1)  Assessment of trust income distributable to nonresident beneficiary. The income of a trust distributable or distributed to a nonresident beneficiary shall be assessed as the income of other nonresidents is assessed.  No personal exemptions shall be allowed in assessing the income of such nonresident beneficiary unless that beneficiary makes a complete return under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.17(2)  Lien on trust estate; income taxes levied against beneficiary. All income taxes levied against the income of beneficiaries shall be a lien on that portion of the trust estate or interest therein from which the income taxed is derived, and such taxes shall be paid by the fiduciary, if not paid by the distributee, before the same become delinquent.  Every person who, as a fiduciary under the provisions of this subchapter, pays an income tax shall have all the rights and remedies of reimbursement for any taxes assessed against him or her or paid by him or her in such capacity, as provided in s.70.19 (1), 2021 stats., and s.70.19 (2), 2021 stats.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.17(3)  Liability for payment of taxes due from decedent. Any income, withholding, sales, or use taxes, penalties, interest, and costs found to be due from a decedent, an estate, or a trust for any of the years open to assessment under s.71.77and any delinquent income, withholding, sales, or use taxes, penalties, interest, and costs found to be due shall be assessed against and paid by one of the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.17(4)  Trusts established or maintained out-of-state; grantor liable for tax. The establishment or maintenance of a trust outside Wisconsin by a Wisconsin resident as grantor, the income from which trust is taxable to the grantor or to any person other than the trust under the internal revenue code, is hereby declared to be a tax avoidance device designed to avoid the legal application of the Wisconsin income tax to income properly taxable to the grantor or such other person.  Any Wisconsin resident who is the grantor of such a trust shall be liable for the Wisconsin income tax on the income of such trust which is federally taxable to such grantor or other person under the internal revenue code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.17(5)  Trusts that are exempt from federal income tax. Trusts exempt from federal income tax pursuant to subtitle A, chapter 1, subchapter F of the internal revenue code shall to the same extent be exempt from taxation under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.17(6)  Funeral trusts. If a qualified funeral trust makes the election under section685of the Internal Revenue Code for federal income tax purposes, that election applies for purposes of this chapter and each trust shall compute its own tax and shall apply the rates under s.71.06 (1),(1m),(1n),(1p),(1q), or(1r).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.20(1)  Every partnership shall furnish to the department a true and accurate statement, on or before the date on which the partnership is required to file for federal income tax purposes, not including any extension, under the Internal Revenue Code, in the manner and form and setting forth the facts the department deems necessary to enforce this chapter.  A partnership that is the owner of a single-owner entity that is disregarded as a separate entity under section7701of the Internal Revenue Code shall include that entity’s information on the owner’s return under this subchapter.  The statement shall be subscribed by one of the partners of the partnership.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.20(1m)  Every partnership that is required to file a return under sub.(1)shall, on or before the due date of the return, including extensions, provide a schedule to each partner whose share of income, deductions, credits, or other items of the partnership may affect the partner’s tax liability under this chapter.  The schedule shall separately indicate the partner’s share of each item.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.20(2)  Nothing in this section precludes the department of revenue from requiring any person other than a corporation to file an income tax return when in the judgment of the department a return should be filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.20(3)  Any extension granted by law or by the Internal Revenue Service for the filing of the federal return that corresponds to the return required under sub.(1)extends the time for filing under this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(1)  The net income of a partnership shall be computed in the same manner and on the same basis as provided for computation of the income of persons other than corporations.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(2)  The standard deduction shall not be allowed in computing the taxable income of a partnership.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(3)  The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a partnership or by partners, including partners of a publicly traded partnership.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(4)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(5)  Section164(a) (3) of the internal revenue code is modified so that state taxes and taxes of the District of Columbia that are value-added taxes, single business taxes or taxes on or measured by all or a portion of net income, gross income, gross receipts or capital stock are not deductible.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(6)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(7)  A deduction under the Internal Revenue Code for moving expenses, as defined in s.71.01 (8j), paid or incurred during the taxable year to move the taxpayer’s Wisconsin business operation, in whole or in part, to a location outside the state or to move the taxpayer’s business operations outside the United States is not allowed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1e">
            <num>(1e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1e)  “Broadcaster” means a television or radio station licensed by the federal communications commission, a television or radio broadcast network, a cable television network, or a television distribution company.  “Broadcaster” does not include a cable service provider, a direct broadcast satellite system, or an Internet content distributor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1g)  For purposes of s.71.25 (9) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “commercial domicile” means the location from which a trade or business is principally managed and directed, based on any factors the department determines are appropriate, including the location where the greatest number of employees of the trade or business work, have their office or base of operations, or from which the employees are directed or controlled.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1k">
            <num>(1k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1k)  “Corporation” includes corporations, publicly traded partnerships treated as corporations in section7704of the internal revenue code, limited liability companies treated as corporations under the internal revenue code, joint stock companies, associations, common law trusts and all other entities treated as corporations under section7701of the Internal Revenue Code, unless the context requires otherwise.  A single-owner entity that is disregarded as a separate entity under section7701of the Internal Revenue Code is disregarded as a separate entity under this chapter, and its owner is subject to the tax on or measured by the entity’s income. “Corporation” does not include any entity that is a qualified subchapter S subsidiary under s.71.365 (7).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1r">
            <num>(1r)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1r)  “Doing business in this state” includes, except as prohibited under P.L.86-272, issuing credit, debit, or travel and entertainment cards to customers in this state; regularly selling products or services of any kind or nature to customers in this state that receive the product or service in this state; regularly soliciting business from potential customers in this state; regularly performing services outside this state for which the benefits are received in this state; regularly engaging in transactions with customers in this state that involve intangible property and result in receipts flowing to the taxpayer from within this state; holding loans secured by real or tangible personal property located in this state; owning, directly or indirectly, a general or limited partnership interest in a partnership that does business in this state, regardless of the percentage of ownership; and owning, directly or indirectly, an interest in a limited liability company that does business in this state, regardless of the percentage of ownership, if the limited liability company is treated as a partnership for federal income tax purposes.  A taxpayer doing business in this state for any part of the taxable year is considered to be doing business in this state for the entire taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1t">
            <num>(1t)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1t)  For purposes of s.71.25 (9) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “domicile” means an individual’s true, fixed, and permanent home where the individual intends to remain permanently and indefinitely and to which, whenever absent, the individual intends to return, except that no individual may have more than one domicile at any time.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_1tm">
            <num>(1tm)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1tm)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(2)  “Entertainment corporation” means a domestic or foreign corporation which derives income from amusement, entertainment or sporting events in this state or from the services of an entertainer, as defined in s.71.01 (2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_2m">
            <num>(2m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(2m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3)  “Gain” means gain as computed under the internal revenue code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3g">
            <num>(3g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3g)  For purposes of ss.71.26 (2) (a) 7.and9.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in determining net income under the Internal Revenue Code as modified under s.71.26 (3):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3h">
            <num>(3h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3h)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_3m">
            <num>(3m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3m)  For purposes of ss.71.26 (2) (a) 7.and9.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified under s.71.26 (3).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-21__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(4)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-22">
          <num>71.22</num>
          <heading>Computation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.20(1m)  Every partnership that is required to file a return under sub.(1)shall, on or before the due date of the return, including extensions, provide a schedule to each partner whose share of income, deductions, credits, or other items of the partnership may affect the partner’s tax liability under this chapter.  The schedule shall separately indicate the partner’s share of each item.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.20(2)  Nothing in this section precludes the department of revenue from requiring any person other than a corporation to file an income tax return when in the judgment of the department a return should be filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.20(3)  Any extension granted by law or by the Internal Revenue Service for the filing of the federal return that corresponds to the return required under sub.(1)extends the time for filing under this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(1)  The net income of a partnership shall be computed in the same manner and on the same basis as provided for computation of the income of persons other than corporations.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(2)  The standard deduction shall not be allowed in computing the taxable income of a partnership.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(3)  The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a partnership or by partners, including partners of a publicly traded partnership.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(4)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(5)  Section164(a) (3) of the internal revenue code is modified so that state taxes and taxes of the District of Columbia that are value-added taxes, single business taxes or taxes on or measured by all or a portion of net income, gross income, gross receipts or capital stock are not deductible.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(6)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.21(7)  A deduction under the Internal Revenue Code for moving expenses, as defined in s.71.01 (8j), paid or incurred during the taxable year to move the taxpayer’s Wisconsin business operation, in whole or in part, to a location outside the state or to move the taxpayer’s business operations outside the United States is not allowed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1e">
            <num>(1e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1e)  “Broadcaster” means a television or radio station licensed by the federal communications commission, a television or radio broadcast network, a cable television network, or a television distribution company.  “Broadcaster” does not include a cable service provider, a direct broadcast satellite system, or an Internet content distributor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1g)  For purposes of s.71.25 (9) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “commercial domicile” means the location from which a trade or business is principally managed and directed, based on any factors the department determines are appropriate, including the location where the greatest number of employees of the trade or business work, have their office or base of operations, or from which the employees are directed or controlled.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1k">
            <num>(1k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1k)  “Corporation” includes corporations, publicly traded partnerships treated as corporations in section7704of the internal revenue code, limited liability companies treated as corporations under the internal revenue code, joint stock companies, associations, common law trusts and all other entities treated as corporations under section7701of the Internal Revenue Code, unless the context requires otherwise.  A single-owner entity that is disregarded as a separate entity under section7701of the Internal Revenue Code is disregarded as a separate entity under this chapter, and its owner is subject to the tax on or measured by the entity’s income. “Corporation” does not include any entity that is a qualified subchapter S subsidiary under s.71.365 (7).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1r">
            <num>(1r)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1r)  “Doing business in this state” includes, except as prohibited under P.L.86-272, issuing credit, debit, or travel and entertainment cards to customers in this state; regularly selling products or services of any kind or nature to customers in this state that receive the product or service in this state; regularly soliciting business from potential customers in this state; regularly performing services outside this state for which the benefits are received in this state; regularly engaging in transactions with customers in this state that involve intangible property and result in receipts flowing to the taxpayer from within this state; holding loans secured by real or tangible personal property located in this state; owning, directly or indirectly, a general or limited partnership interest in a partnership that does business in this state, regardless of the percentage of ownership; and owning, directly or indirectly, an interest in a limited liability company that does business in this state, regardless of the percentage of ownership, if the limited liability company is treated as a partnership for federal income tax purposes.  A taxpayer doing business in this state for any part of the taxable year is considered to be doing business in this state for the entire taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1t">
            <num>(1t)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1t)  For purposes of s.71.25 (9) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “domicile” means an individual’s true, fixed, and permanent home where the individual intends to remain permanently and indefinitely and to which, whenever absent, the individual intends to return, except that no individual may have more than one domicile at any time.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_1tm">
            <num>(1tm)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(1tm)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(2)  “Entertainment corporation” means a domestic or foreign corporation which derives income from amusement, entertainment or sporting events in this state or from the services of an entertainer, as defined in s.71.01 (2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_2m">
            <num>(2m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(2m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3)  “Gain” means gain as computed under the internal revenue code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_3g">
            <num>(3g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3g)  For purposes of ss.71.26 (2) (a) 7.and9.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in determining net income under the Internal Revenue Code as modified under s.71.26 (3):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_3h">
            <num>(3h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3h)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_3m">
            <num>(3m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(3m)  For purposes of ss.71.26 (2) (a) 7.and9.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified under s.71.26 (3).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-22__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(4)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-23">
          <num>71.23</num>
          <heading>Imposition of tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_5s">
            <num>(5s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(5s)  “Last day prescribed by law” has the meaning given in s.71.738.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(6)  “Loss” means loss as computed under the internal revenue code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_6d">
            <num>(6d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(6d)  For purposes of s.71.26 (2) (a) 7.and9., “management fees” include expenses and costs, not including interest expenses, pertaining to accounts receivable, accounts payable, employee benefit plans, insurance, legal matters, payroll, data processing, purchasing, taxation, financial matters, securities, accounting, or reporting and compliance matters or similar activities, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in determining net income under the Internal Revenue Code as modified by s.71.26 (3).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_6m">
            <num>(6m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(6m)  “Member” does not include a member of a limited liability company treated as a corporation under sub.(1k).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(7)  “Nuclear decommissioning reserve fund” and “nuclear decommissioning trust fund” have the meanings under section468Aof the internal revenue code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_7m">
            <num>(7m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(7m)  “Partner” does not include a partner of a publicly traded partnership treated as a corporation under sub.(1k).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(8)  “Pay”, in regard to submissions to persons other than the department, has the meaning appropriate to the taxpayer’s method of accounting.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9)  “Person” includes corporations, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_9ad">
            <num>(9ad)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9ad)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_9am">
            <num>(9am)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9am)  “Related entity” means any person related to a taxpayer as provided under section267or1563of the Internal Revenue Code during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year and any real estate investment trust under section856of the Internal Revenue Code, except a qualified real estate investment trust, if more than 50 percent of any class of the beneficial interests or shares of the real estate investment trust are owned directly, indirectly, or constructively by the taxpayer, or any person related to the taxpayer, during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year.  For purposes of this subsection, the constructive ownership rules of section318(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified by section856(d) (5) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall apply in determining the ownership of stock, assets, or net profits of any person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_9an">
            <num>(9an)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9an)  For purposes of s.71.26 (2) (a) 7.and9., “rental expenses” means the gross amounts that would otherwise be deductible under the Internal Revenue Code, as modified under s.71.26 (3), for the use of, or the right to use, real property and tangible personal property in connection with real property, including services furnished or rendered in connection with such property, regardless of how reported for financial accounting purposes and regardless of how computed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_9g">
            <num>(9g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9g)  For purposes of s.71.25 (9) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “state” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States, unless the context requires that “state” means only the state of Wisconsin.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9m)  “Subscribe” means write one’s signature or, if the department prescribes another method of authenticating, use that other method.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(10)  “Taxable year” means the taxable period upon the basis of which the taxable income of the taxpayer is computed for federal income tax purposes.  The taxable year of a corporation that keeps its accounting records on the basis of a 52-53 week period ends on the last day of the month closest to the end of the 52-53 week period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(11)  Except as provided in s.71.45 (2), “Wisconsin net income”, for corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, means net income and, for corporations engaged in business both within and outside this state, means the amount assigned to this state under s.71.25 (6),(10) (c)or(13)or by a separate accounting or allocation, if allowed under s.71.25 (6), or by another method approved under s.71.25 (11),(12)or(14).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.23(1)  Income tax. For the purpose of raising revenue for the state and the counties, cities, villages and towns, there shall be assessed, levied, collected and paid a tax as provided under this chapter on all Wisconsin net incomes of corporations that are not subject to the franchise tax under sub.(2)and that own property within this state; that derive income from sources within this state or from activities that are attributable to this state; or whose business within this state during the taxable year, except as provided under sub.(3), consists exclusively of foreign commerce, interstate commerce, or both, or that buy or sell lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state; except as exempted under s.71.26 (1).  This section shall not be construed to prevent or affect the correction of errors or omissions in the assessments of income for former years under s.71.74 (1)and(2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.23(2)  Franchise tax. For the privilege of exercising its franchise, buying or selling lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state or doing business in this state in a corporate capacity, except as provided under sub.(3), every domestic or foreign corporation, except corporations specified in s.71.26 (1), and every nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve fund shall annually pay a franchise tax according to or measured by its entire Wisconsin net income of the preceding taxable year at the rate set forth in s.71.27 (2).  In addition, except as provided in sub.(3)and s.71.26 (1), a corporation that ceases doing business in this state and a nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve fund that is terminated shall pay a special franchise tax according to or measured by its entire Wisconsin net income for the taxable year during which the corporation ceases doing business in this state or the nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve fund is terminated at the rates under s.71.27 (2).  Every corporation organized under the laws of this state shall be deemed to be residing within this state for the purposes of this franchise tax.  All provisions of this chapter and ch.73relating to income taxation of corporations shall apply to franchise taxes imposed under this subsection, unless the context requires otherwise.  The tax imposed by this subsection on national banking associations shall be in lieu of all taxes imposed by this state on national banking associations to the extent it is not permissible to tax such associations under federal law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.23(3)  Activities that do not create nexus.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(1)  Filing returns. Every corporation, except a corporation all of whose income is exempt from taxation and except as provided in sub.(1m), shall furnish to the department a true and accurate statement, on or before the date on which the corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, not including any extension, under the Internal Revenue Code, in the manner and form and setting forth the facts the department deems necessary to enforce this chapter.  Every corporation that is required to furnish a statement under this subsection and that has income that is not taxable under this subchapter shall include with the corporation’s statement a report that identifies each item of the corporation’s nontaxable income.  The statement shall be subscribed by the president, vice president, treasurer, assistant treasurer, chief accounting officer, or any other officer duly authorized so to act.  In the case of a return made for a corporation by a fiduciary, the fiduciary shall subscribe the return.  The fact that an individual’s name is subscribed on the return shall be prima facie evidence that the individual is authorized to subscribe the return on behalf of the corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(1m)  Unrelated business income statement. Every corporation subject to a tax on unrelated business income under s.71.26 (1) (a), if that corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, shall furnish to the department a true and accurate statement on or before the date on which the corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, not including any extension, under the Internal Revenue Code.  The requirements about manner, form, and subscription under sub.(1)apply to statements under this subsection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(2)  Copies of federal return. Each corporation that is required to file a return under this section shall file with that return a copy of its federal income tax return for the same taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(3)  Inactive corporations. Whenever a corporation has been completely inactive for an entire taxable year, in lieu of filing the statements and information otherwise required by this section, it may file a declaration, on a form to be provided by the department, subscribed by its president, if a resident of this state, and, if not a resident, then by another officer residing in this state, attesting to such inactivity.  Such declaration must be filed prior to the otherwise due date for its Wisconsin return for such taxable year.  Thereafter the corporation need not file such statements or information for any subsequent year unless specifically requested to do so by the department or unless in a subsequent year the corporation has been activated or reactivated.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(4)  Filing returns by receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or assignee. If a receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or assignee, by order of a court, by operation of law or otherwise, has possession of all or substantially all of the property or business of a corporation, whether or not such property or business is being operated, such receiver, trustee or assignee shall make the return of income for such corporation in the manner and form that corporations are required to make such returns.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(5)  Department may require filing. Nothing contained in this section shall preclude the department from requiring any corporation to file a return when in the judgment of the department a return should be filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(6)  Changing reporting period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(7)  Extensions.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(9)  Delinquencies.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(10)  Advance payments. The department of revenue shall accept in advance income or franchise taxes and surtaxes from taxpayers desirous of making such payments before the same shall become due and payable.  Advance payment of taxes under this subsection shall not relieve the taxpayer from additional taxes which may result from subsequent legislation or from additional taxable income disclosed or discovered subsequent to such payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(11)  Small balances. No person is required to pay a balance due of less than $1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(1)  Beneficiaries. The situs of income derived by any taxpayer as the beneficiary of the estate of a decedent or of a trust estate shall be determined as if such income had been received without the intervention of a fiduciary.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(2)  Grantor trusts. The situs of income received by a trustee, which income, under the internal revenue code, is taxable to the grantor of the trust or to any person other than the trust, shall be determined as if such income had been actually received directly by such grantor or such other person, without the intervention of the trust.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(4)  Corporations engaged in business wholly within this state. For corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, all income is subject to, or included in the measure of, the Wisconsin income or franchise tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-23__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(5)  Corporations engaged in business both within and without the state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-24">
          <num>71.24</num>
          <heading>Imposition of tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_9am">
            <num>(9am)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9am)  “Related entity” means any person related to a taxpayer as provided under section267or1563of the Internal Revenue Code during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year and any real estate investment trust under section856of the Internal Revenue Code, except a qualified real estate investment trust, if more than 50 percent of any class of the beneficial interests or shares of the real estate investment trust are owned directly, indirectly, or constructively by the taxpayer, or any person related to the taxpayer, during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year.  For purposes of this subsection, the constructive ownership rules of section318(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified by section856(d) (5) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall apply in determining the ownership of stock, assets, or net profits of any person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_9an">
            <num>(9an)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9an)  For purposes of s.71.26 (2) (a) 7.and9., “rental expenses” means the gross amounts that would otherwise be deductible under the Internal Revenue Code, as modified under s.71.26 (3), for the use of, or the right to use, real property and tangible personal property in connection with real property, including services furnished or rendered in connection with such property, regardless of how reported for financial accounting purposes and regardless of how computed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_9g">
            <num>(9g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9g)  For purposes of s.71.25 (9) (df),(dh),(dj), and(dk), “state” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States, unless the context requires that “state” means only the state of Wisconsin.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(9m)  “Subscribe” means write one’s signature or, if the department prescribes another method of authenticating, use that other method.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(10)  “Taxable year” means the taxable period upon the basis of which the taxable income of the taxpayer is computed for federal income tax purposes.  The taxable year of a corporation that keeps its accounting records on the basis of a 52-53 week period ends on the last day of the month closest to the end of the 52-53 week period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.22(11)  Except as provided in s.71.45 (2), “Wisconsin net income”, for corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, means net income and, for corporations engaged in business both within and outside this state, means the amount assigned to this state under s.71.25 (6),(10) (c)or(13)or by a separate accounting or allocation, if allowed under s.71.25 (6), or by another method approved under s.71.25 (11),(12)or(14).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.23(1)  Income tax. For the purpose of raising revenue for the state and the counties, cities, villages and towns, there shall be assessed, levied, collected and paid a tax as provided under this chapter on all Wisconsin net incomes of corporations that are not subject to the franchise tax under sub.(2)and that own property within this state; that derive income from sources within this state or from activities that are attributable to this state; or whose business within this state during the taxable year, except as provided under sub.(3), consists exclusively of foreign commerce, interstate commerce, or both, or that buy or sell lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state; except as exempted under s.71.26 (1).  This section shall not be construed to prevent or affect the correction of errors or omissions in the assessments of income for former years under s.71.74 (1)and(2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.23(2)  Franchise tax. For the privilege of exercising its franchise, buying or selling lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state or doing business in this state in a corporate capacity, except as provided under sub.(3), every domestic or foreign corporation, except corporations specified in s.71.26 (1), and every nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve fund shall annually pay a franchise tax according to or measured by its entire Wisconsin net income of the preceding taxable year at the rate set forth in s.71.27 (2).  In addition, except as provided in sub.(3)and s.71.26 (1), a corporation that ceases doing business in this state and a nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve fund that is terminated shall pay a special franchise tax according to or measured by its entire Wisconsin net income for the taxable year during which the corporation ceases doing business in this state or the nuclear decommissioning trust or reserve fund is terminated at the rates under s.71.27 (2).  Every corporation organized under the laws of this state shall be deemed to be residing within this state for the purposes of this franchise tax.  All provisions of this chapter and ch.73relating to income taxation of corporations shall apply to franchise taxes imposed under this subsection, unless the context requires otherwise.  The tax imposed by this subsection on national banking associations shall be in lieu of all taxes imposed by this state on national banking associations to the extent it is not permissible to tax such associations under federal law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.23(3)  Activities that do not create nexus.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(1)  Filing returns. Every corporation, except a corporation all of whose income is exempt from taxation and except as provided in sub.(1m), shall furnish to the department a true and accurate statement, on or before the date on which the corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, not including any extension, under the Internal Revenue Code, in the manner and form and setting forth the facts the department deems necessary to enforce this chapter.  Every corporation that is required to furnish a statement under this subsection and that has income that is not taxable under this subchapter shall include with the corporation’s statement a report that identifies each item of the corporation’s nontaxable income.  The statement shall be subscribed by the president, vice president, treasurer, assistant treasurer, chief accounting officer, or any other officer duly authorized so to act.  In the case of a return made for a corporation by a fiduciary, the fiduciary shall subscribe the return.  The fact that an individual’s name is subscribed on the return shall be prima facie evidence that the individual is authorized to subscribe the return on behalf of the corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(1m)  Unrelated business income statement. Every corporation subject to a tax on unrelated business income under s.71.26 (1) (a), if that corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, shall furnish to the department a true and accurate statement on or before the date on which the corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, not including any extension, under the Internal Revenue Code.  The requirements about manner, form, and subscription under sub.(1)apply to statements under this subsection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(2)  Copies of federal return. Each corporation that is required to file a return under this section shall file with that return a copy of its federal income tax return for the same taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(3)  Inactive corporations. Whenever a corporation has been completely inactive for an entire taxable year, in lieu of filing the statements and information otherwise required by this section, it may file a declaration, on a form to be provided by the department, subscribed by its president, if a resident of this state, and, if not a resident, then by another officer residing in this state, attesting to such inactivity.  Such declaration must be filed prior to the otherwise due date for its Wisconsin return for such taxable year.  Thereafter the corporation need not file such statements or information for any subsequent year unless specifically requested to do so by the department or unless in a subsequent year the corporation has been activated or reactivated.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(4)  Filing returns by receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or assignee. If a receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or assignee, by order of a court, by operation of law or otherwise, has possession of all or substantially all of the property or business of a corporation, whether or not such property or business is being operated, such receiver, trustee or assignee shall make the return of income for such corporation in the manner and form that corporations are required to make such returns.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(5)  Department may require filing. Nothing contained in this section shall preclude the department from requiring any corporation to file a return when in the judgment of the department a return should be filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(6)  Changing reporting period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(7)  Extensions.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(9)  Delinquencies.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(10)  Advance payments. The department of revenue shall accept in advance income or franchise taxes and surtaxes from taxpayers desirous of making such payments before the same shall become due and payable.  Advance payment of taxes under this subsection shall not relieve the taxpayer from additional taxes which may result from subsequent legislation or from additional taxable income disclosed or discovered subsequent to such payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(11)  Small balances. No person is required to pay a balance due of less than $1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(1)  Beneficiaries. The situs of income derived by any taxpayer as the beneficiary of the estate of a decedent or of a trust estate shall be determined as if such income had been received without the intervention of a fiduciary.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(2)  Grantor trusts. The situs of income received by a trustee, which income, under the internal revenue code, is taxable to the grantor of the trust or to any person other than the trust, shall be determined as if such income had been actually received directly by such grantor or such other person, without the intervention of the trust.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(4)  Corporations engaged in business wholly within this state. For corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, all income is subject to, or included in the measure of, the Wisconsin income or franchise tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(5)  Corporations engaged in business both within and without the state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-24__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(6)  Allocation and separate accounting and apportionment formula. Corporations engaged in business within and without the state shall be taxed only on such income as is derived from business transacted and property located within the state.  The amount of such income attributable to Wisconsin may be determined by an allocation and separate accounting thereof, when the business of such corporation within the state is not an integral part of a unitary business, but the department of revenue may permit an allocation and separate accounting in any case in which it is satisfied that the use of such method will properly reflect the income taxable by this state.  In all cases in which allocation and separate accounting is not permissible, the determination shall be made in the following manner: for all businesses except air carriers, financial organizations, telecommunications companies, pipeline companies, public utilities, railroads, car line companies and corporations or associations that are subject to a tax on unrelated business income under s.71.26 (1) (a)there shall first be deducted from the total net income of the taxpayer the part thereof (less related expenses, if any) that follows the situs of the property or the residence of the recipient.  The remaining net income shall be apportioned to this state by use of the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-25">
          <num>71.25</num>
          <heading>Filing returns; extensions; payment of tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(1)  Filing returns. Every corporation, except a corporation all of whose income is exempt from taxation and except as provided in sub.(1m), shall furnish to the department a true and accurate statement, on or before the date on which the corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, not including any extension, under the Internal Revenue Code, in the manner and form and setting forth the facts the department deems necessary to enforce this chapter.  Every corporation that is required to furnish a statement under this subsection and that has income that is not taxable under this subchapter shall include with the corporation’s statement a report that identifies each item of the corporation’s nontaxable income.  The statement shall be subscribed by the president, vice president, treasurer, assistant treasurer, chief accounting officer, or any other officer duly authorized so to act.  In the case of a return made for a corporation by a fiduciary, the fiduciary shall subscribe the return.  The fact that an individual’s name is subscribed on the return shall be prima facie evidence that the individual is authorized to subscribe the return on behalf of the corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(1m)  Unrelated business income statement. Every corporation subject to a tax on unrelated business income under s.71.26 (1) (a), if that corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, shall furnish to the department a true and accurate statement on or before the date on which the corporation is required to file for federal income tax purposes, not including any extension, under the Internal Revenue Code.  The requirements about manner, form, and subscription under sub.(1)apply to statements under this subsection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(2)  Copies of federal return. Each corporation that is required to file a return under this section shall file with that return a copy of its federal income tax return for the same taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(3)  Inactive corporations. Whenever a corporation has been completely inactive for an entire taxable year, in lieu of filing the statements and information otherwise required by this section, it may file a declaration, on a form to be provided by the department, subscribed by its president, if a resident of this state, and, if not a resident, then by another officer residing in this state, attesting to such inactivity.  Such declaration must be filed prior to the otherwise due date for its Wisconsin return for such taxable year.  Thereafter the corporation need not file such statements or information for any subsequent year unless specifically requested to do so by the department or unless in a subsequent year the corporation has been activated or reactivated.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(4)  Filing returns by receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or assignee. If a receiver, trustee in bankruptcy or assignee, by order of a court, by operation of law or otherwise, has possession of all or substantially all of the property or business of a corporation, whether or not such property or business is being operated, such receiver, trustee or assignee shall make the return of income for such corporation in the manner and form that corporations are required to make such returns.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(5)  Department may require filing. Nothing contained in this section shall preclude the department from requiring any corporation to file a return when in the judgment of the department a return should be filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(6)  Changing reporting period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(7)  Extensions.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(9)  Delinquencies.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(10)  Advance payments. The department of revenue shall accept in advance income or franchise taxes and surtaxes from taxpayers desirous of making such payments before the same shall become due and payable.  Advance payment of taxes under this subsection shall not relieve the taxpayer from additional taxes which may result from subsequent legislation or from additional taxable income disclosed or discovered subsequent to such payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.24(11)  Small balances. No person is required to pay a balance due of less than $1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(1)  Beneficiaries. The situs of income derived by any taxpayer as the beneficiary of the estate of a decedent or of a trust estate shall be determined as if such income had been received without the intervention of a fiduciary.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(2)  Grantor trusts. The situs of income received by a trustee, which income, under the internal revenue code, is taxable to the grantor of the trust or to any person other than the trust, shall be determined as if such income had been actually received directly by such grantor or such other person, without the intervention of the trust.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(4)  Corporations engaged in business wholly within this state. For corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, all income is subject to, or included in the measure of, the Wisconsin income or franchise tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(5)  Corporations engaged in business both within and without the state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(6)  Allocation and separate accounting and apportionment formula. Corporations engaged in business within and without the state shall be taxed only on such income as is derived from business transacted and property located within the state.  The amount of such income attributable to Wisconsin may be determined by an allocation and separate accounting thereof, when the business of such corporation within the state is not an integral part of a unitary business, but the department of revenue may permit an allocation and separate accounting in any case in which it is satisfied that the use of such method will properly reflect the income taxable by this state.  In all cases in which allocation and separate accounting is not permissible, the determination shall be made in the following manner: for all businesses except air carriers, financial organizations, telecommunications companies, pipeline companies, public utilities, railroads, car line companies and corporations or associations that are subject to a tax on unrelated business income under s.71.26 (1) (a)there shall first be deducted from the total net income of the taxpayer the part thereof (less related expenses, if any) that follows the situs of the property or the residence of the recipient.  The remaining net income shall be apportioned to this state by use of the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_6m">
            <num>(6m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(6m)  Apportionment formula computation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(7)  Property factor. For purposes of sub.(6)and for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2008:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-25__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(8)  Payroll factor. For purposes of sub.(6)and for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2008:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-255">
          <num>71.255</num>
          <heading>Combined reporting</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(10)  Railroads, financial organizations and public utilities.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(11)  Department may waive factor. Where, in the case of any corporation engaged in business in and outside of this state and required to apportion its income as provided in sub.(6), it shall be shown to the satisfaction of the department of revenue that the use of any one of the 3 factors provided in sub.(6)gives an unreasonable or inequitable final average ratio because of the fact that such corporation does not employ, to any appreciable extent in its trade or business in producing the income taxed, the factors made use of in obtaining such ratio, this factor may, with the approval of the department of revenue, be omitted in obtaining the final average ratio which is to be applied to the remaining net income.  This subsection does not apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2007.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(12)  Department may apportion by rule. If the income of any such corporation properly assignable to the state of Wisconsin cannot be ascertained with reasonable certainty by the methods under this section, then the same shall be apportioned and allocated under such rules as the department of revenue may prescribe.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(13)  Unrelated business taxable income. The unrelated business taxable income of organizations that are subject to tax on that income under s.71.26 (1) (a)shall be apportioned under the department of revenue’s rules.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(14)  Alternative allocation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(15)  Partnerships and limited liability companies.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.25(16)  Disaster relief work. For purposes of the apportionment of any income under this section, the disaster relief work, as defined in s.323.12 (5) (a) 3., of an out-of-state business, as defined in s.323.12 (5) (a) 6., shall not increase the amount of income apportioned to this state.  For purposes of sub.(7), any property brought temporarily into this state by an out-of-state business in connection with performing disaster relief work is not considered property located in this state.  For purposes of sub.(8), compensation paid to out-of-state employees, as defined in s.323.12 (5) (a) 7., who are performing disaster relief work is not considered compensation paid in this state.  For purposes of sub.(9), gross receipts from the sale of property or services as part of performing any disaster relief work are not considered gross receipts from sales received in this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(1)  Definitions. In this section:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(2)  Corporations required to use combined reporting.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_2m">
            <num>(2m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(2m)  Election to include every member of commonly controlled group.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(3)  Components of income subject to tax. Each member is responsible for tax based on its taxable income or loss apportioned or allocated to this state, including:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-255__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(4)  Business income of the combined group.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-26">
          <num>71.26</num>
          <heading>Income computation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(7)  Designated agent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(8)  Taxable year of combined group. The combined group’s taxable year is determined as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(9)  Part-year members of a combined group. If a corporation becomes a member of a combined group or ceases to be a member of a combined group after the beginning of the taxable year of the combined group, the corporation’s income shall be determined as provided under subs.(3),(4), and(5)for the portion of the year in which the corporation was a member of the combined group and that income shall be included in the combined report.  The income for the remaining short period shall be reported on a separate return or separate combined report.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(10)  Transition. The department shall deem timely paid the estimated tax payments attributable to income includable in the combined report for installments that become due during the period beginning on January 1, 2009, and ending on March 6, 2009, provided that such estimated tax payments are paid by the next installment due date that follows in sequence following March 6, 2009.  However, if the next installment due date that follows in sequence following March 6, 2009, is less than 45 days after March 6, 2009, such estimated tax payments, in addition to the payment due less than 45 days after March 6, 2009, shall be deemed timely paid if paid by the next subsequent installment due date.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.255(11)  Conformity with federal consolidated return regulations. The department may promulgate any rules necessary to create uniformity between the treatment of transactions entered into by members of a federal consolidated group under federal regulations, including any income, expense, gain, or loss limitations applicable to such transactions, and treatment of transactions entered into by members of a combined group under this section, including any income, expense, gain, or loss limitations applicable to such transactions.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.26(1)  Exempt and excludable income. There shall be exempt from taxation under this subchapter income as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.26(1m)  Exemption from the income tax. The interest and income from the following obligations are exempt from the tax imposed under s.71.23 (1):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-26__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.26(2)  Net income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-265">
          <num>71.265</num>
          <heading>Previously exempt corporations; basis and depreciation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-265__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.26(4)  Net business loss carry-forward.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-265__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(1)  The taxes to be assessed, levied and collected upon Wisconsin net incomes of corporations shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-265__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(2)  The corporation franchise tax imposed under s.71.23 (2)and measured by Wisconsin net income shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-265__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1)  Community development finance credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-265__subsec_1dm">
            <num>(1dm)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dm)  Development zone capital investment credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-265__subsec_1dx">
            <num>(1dx)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dx)  Development zones credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-265__subsec_1dy">
            <num>(1dy)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dy)  Economic development tax credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-27">
          <num>71.27</num>
          <heading>Previously exempt corporations; basis and depreciation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-27__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.26(4)  Net business loss carry-forward.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(1)  The taxes to be assessed, levied and collected upon Wisconsin net incomes of corporations shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(2)  The corporation franchise tax imposed under s.71.23 (2)and measured by Wisconsin net income shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1)  Community development finance credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-27__subsec_1dm">
            <num>(1dm)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dm)  Development zone capital investment credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-27__subsec_1dx">
            <num>(1dx)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dx)  Development zones credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-27__subsec_1dy">
            <num>(1dy)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dy)  Economic development tax credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-275">
          <num>71.275</num>
          <heading>Previously exempt corporations; basis and depreciation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-275__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.26(4)  Net business loss carry-forward.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-275__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(1)  The taxes to be assessed, levied and collected upon Wisconsin net incomes of corporations shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-275__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(2)  The corporation franchise tax imposed under s.71.23 (2)and measured by Wisconsin net income shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-275__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1)  Community development finance credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-275__subsec_1dm">
            <num>(1dm)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dm)  Development zone capital investment credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-275__subsec_1dx">
            <num>(1dx)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dx)  Development zones credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-275__subsec_1dy">
            <num>(1dy)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dy)  Economic development tax credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-28">
          <num>71.28</num>
          <heading>Previously exempt corporations; basis and depreciation</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.26(4)  Net business loss carry-forward.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(1)  The taxes to be assessed, levied and collected upon Wisconsin net incomes of corporations shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.27(2)  The corporation franchise tax imposed under s.71.23 (2)and measured by Wisconsin net income shall be computed at the rate of 7.9 percent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1)  Community development finance credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_1dm">
            <num>(1dm)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dm)  Development zone capital investment credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_1dx">
            <num>(1dx)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dx)  Development zones credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_1dy">
            <num>(1dy)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(1dy)  Economic development tax credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(2)  Farmland preservation credit. The farmland preservation credit under subch.IXmay be claimed against taxes otherwise due subject to the provisions, requirements and conditions of that subchapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-28__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(3)  Manufacturing sales tax credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-29">
          <num>71.29</num>
          <heading>Payments of estimated taxes</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_8b">
            <num>(8b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(8b)  Low-income housing credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.28(10)  Employee college savings account contribution credit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(1)  Definitions. In this section:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(2)  Who shall pay. Every corporation subject to tax under s.71.23 (1)or(2)and every virtually exempt entity subject to tax under s.71.125or71.23 (1)or(2)shall pay an estimated tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(3)  Refund carry-forward. If a corporation or virtually exempt entity claims a refund on any tax return and, concurrent with or subsequent to filing the return upon which that refund is claimed, is required to pay an estimated tax, and at the time of paying that tax the refund has not been paid, the corporation or virtually exempt entity may deduct the amount of that refund from the first installment of estimated taxes and may deduct any excess from the succeeding installments.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_3m">
            <num>(3m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(3m)  Refunds. The department of revenue may refund estimated taxes after the completion of the taxable year to which the estimated taxes relate if the refund is at least 10 percent of the taxes estimated for that taxable year and is at least $500.  A refund under this subsection may be subject to s.71.84 (2) (c).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(4)  Prepayments. Any installment of the estimated tax under this section may be paid before the due date.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(5)  Short year. Application of this section to taxable years of less than 12 full months shall be made under the department of revenue’s rules.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(6)  Overpayments. If the amount of an installment payment of estimated tax exceeds the amount determined to be the correct amount of that payment, the overpayment shall be credited against the next unpaid installment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(7)  Exception to interest. No interest is required under s.71.84 (2) (a)or(b)for a corporation or virtually exempt entity if any of the following conditions apply:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(8)  Installment due dates. Taxpayers shall make estimated payments in 4 installments, on or before the 15th day of each of the following months:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(9)  Installment amounts; income of less than $250,000.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(10)  Installment amounts; income of $250,000 or more.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(11)  Exception to final installment. If a corporation or virtually exempt entity files a return for a calendar year on or before January 31 of the succeeding calendar year (or if a corporation or virtually exempt entity on a fiscal year basis files a return on or before the last day of the first month immediately succeeding the close of such fiscal year) and pays in full at the time of such filing the amount computed on the return as payable, then, if estimated taxes are not required to be paid on or before the 15th day of the 9th month of the taxable year but are required to be paid on or before the 15th day of the 12th month of the taxable year, such return shall be considered as payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(1)  Accounting method.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(2)  Allocation of gross income, deductions, credits between 2 or more businesses. In any case of 2 or more organizations, trades or businesses (whether or not incorporated, whether or not organized in the United States, whether or not affiliated, and whether or not unitary) owned or controlled directly or indirectly by the same interests, the secretary or his or her delegate may distribute, apportion or allocate gross income, deductions, credits or allowances between or among such organizations, trades or businesses, if he or she determines that such distribution, apportionment or allocation is necessary in order to prevent evasion of taxes or clearly to reflect the income of any of such organizations, trades or businesses.  The authority granted under this subsection is in addition to, and not a limitation of or dependent on, the provisions of ss.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 45.,71.26 (2) (a) 7.and8.,71.34 (1k) (j)and(k),71.45 (2) (a) 16.and17., and71.80 (23).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_2m">
            <num>(2m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(2m)  Transactions without economic substance.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-29__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(3)  Computations order. Notwithstanding any other provisions in this chapter, corporations computing liability for the tax under s.71.23 (1)or(2)shall make computations in the following order:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-30">
          <num>71.30</num>
          <heading>General provisions</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(3)  Refund carry-forward. If a corporation or virtually exempt entity claims a refund on any tax return and, concurrent with or subsequent to filing the return upon which that refund is claimed, is required to pay an estimated tax, and at the time of paying that tax the refund has not been paid, the corporation or virtually exempt entity may deduct the amount of that refund from the first installment of estimated taxes and may deduct any excess from the succeeding installments.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_3m">
            <num>(3m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(3m)  Refunds. The department of revenue may refund estimated taxes after the completion of the taxable year to which the estimated taxes relate if the refund is at least 10 percent of the taxes estimated for that taxable year and is at least $500.  A refund under this subsection may be subject to s.71.84 (2) (c).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(4)  Prepayments. Any installment of the estimated tax under this section may be paid before the due date.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(5)  Short year. Application of this section to taxable years of less than 12 full months shall be made under the department of revenue’s rules.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(6)  Overpayments. If the amount of an installment payment of estimated tax exceeds the amount determined to be the correct amount of that payment, the overpayment shall be credited against the next unpaid installment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(7)  Exception to interest. No interest is required under s.71.84 (2) (a)or(b)for a corporation or virtually exempt entity if any of the following conditions apply:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(8)  Installment due dates. Taxpayers shall make estimated payments in 4 installments, on or before the 15th day of each of the following months:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(9)  Installment amounts; income of less than $250,000.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(10)  Installment amounts; income of $250,000 or more.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.29(11)  Exception to final installment. If a corporation or virtually exempt entity files a return for a calendar year on or before January 31 of the succeeding calendar year (or if a corporation or virtually exempt entity on a fiscal year basis files a return on or before the last day of the first month immediately succeeding the close of such fiscal year) and pays in full at the time of such filing the amount computed on the return as payable, then, if estimated taxes are not required to be paid on or before the 15th day of the 9th month of the taxable year but are required to be paid on or before the 15th day of the 12th month of the taxable year, such return shall be considered as payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(1)  Accounting method.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(2)  Allocation of gross income, deductions, credits between 2 or more businesses. In any case of 2 or more organizations, trades or businesses (whether or not incorporated, whether or not organized in the United States, whether or not affiliated, and whether or not unitary) owned or controlled directly or indirectly by the same interests, the secretary or his or her delegate may distribute, apportion or allocate gross income, deductions, credits or allowances between or among such organizations, trades or businesses, if he or she determines that such distribution, apportionment or allocation is necessary in order to prevent evasion of taxes or clearly to reflect the income of any of such organizations, trades or businesses.  The authority granted under this subsection is in addition to, and not a limitation of or dependent on, the provisions of ss.71.05 (6) (a) 24.and(b) 45.,71.26 (2) (a) 7.and8.,71.34 (1k) (j)and(k),71.45 (2) (a) 16.and17., and71.80 (23).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_2m">
            <num>(2m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(2m)  Transactions without economic substance.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(3)  Computations order. Notwithstanding any other provisions in this chapter, corporations computing liability for the tax under s.71.23 (1)or(2)shall make computations in the following order:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(4)  Defense contract renegotiation. If the renegotiation or price redetermination of any corporation defense contract or subcontract by the government of the United States or any agency thereof or the voluntary adjustment of prices, costs or profits on any such contract or subcontract results in a reduction of income, the amount of any repayment or credit pursuant to such renegotiation, price redetermination or adjustment, including any federal income taxes credited as a part thereof, shall be allowed as a deduction from the corporate taxable income of the year in which said income was reported for taxation.  Any federal income tax previously paid upon any income so repaid or credited shall be disallowed as a deduction from income of the year in which such tax was originally deducted, to the extent that such tax constituted an allowable deduction for said year.  Any corporate taxpayer affected by such renegotiation, price redetermination or voluntary adjustment may within one year after the final determination thereof file a claim for refund and secure the same without interest, and the department of revenue shall make appropriate adjustments on account of said tax deductions without interest, notwithstanding the limitations of s.71.75or other applicable statutes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(5)  Disc income combining. In the case of a parent corporation, its DISC or affiliate, the net income of a DISC derived from business transacted with its parent shall be combined with the income of the parent corporation and the net income of a DISC derived from business transacted with the parent’s affiliated corporation shall be combined with the net income of the affiliated corporation to determine the amount of income subject to taxation under this chapter for the DISC, the parent corporation or the affiliate of the parent corporation as separate taxable entities.  The net income of the parent corporation shall not include dividends received from the DISC paid from income previously combined for taxation under this subsection.  “DISC” (domestic international sales corporation) has the meaning specified in section992of the internal revenue code as amended to December 31, 1979.  For purposes of this subsection, a corporation is affiliated if at least 50 percent of its total combined voting stock is owned directly or indirectly by its parent corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(6)  Installment method; distributions and final year. A corporation entitled to use the installment method of accounting shall take the unreported balance of gain on all installment obligations into income in the taxable year of their distribution, transfer or acquisition by another person or for the final taxable year for which it files or is required to file a return under this chapter, whichever year occurs first.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(7)  Penalties. Unless specifically provided in this subchapter, the penalties under subch.XIIIapply for failure to comply with the provisions of this subchapter unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(8)  Pricing effect on taxable income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(9)  Reserve account transfer to surplus. If any transfer of a reserve or other account or portion thereof is in effect a transfer to surplus, so much of such transfer as had been accumulated through deductions from the gross or taxable income of the years open to audit under s.71.74 (1)and(2)shall be included in the gross or taxable income of such years, and so much of such transfer as has been accumulated through deductions from the gross or taxable income of the years following January 1, 1911, and not open to audit under s.71.74 (1)and(2)shall be included in the gross or taxable income of the year in which such transfer was effected.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-30__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(10)  Endangered resources.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-32">
          <num>71.32</num>
          <heading>Conformity</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-32__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(11)  Veterans trust fund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-32__subsec_1am">
            <num>(1am)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1am)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-32__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1b)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-32__subsec_1c">
            <num>(1c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1c)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing Wisconsin adjusted gross income:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-32__subsec_1d">
            <num>(1d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1d)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-32__subsec_1e">
            <num>(1e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1e)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code and deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-32__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1g)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-33">
          <num>71.33</num>
          <heading>Conformity</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-33__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(11)  Veterans trust fund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-33__subsec_1am">
            <num>(1am)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1am)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-33__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1b)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-33__subsec_1c">
            <num>(1c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1c)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing Wisconsin adjusted gross income:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-33__subsec_1d">
            <num>(1d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1d)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-33__subsec_1e">
            <num>(1e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1e)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code and deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-33__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1g)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-34">
          <num>71.34</num>
          <heading>Conformity</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-34__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.30(11)  Veterans trust fund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-34__subsec_1am">
            <num>(1am)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1am)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-34__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1b)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-34__subsec_1c">
            <num>(1c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1c)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing Wisconsin adjusted gross income:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-34__subsec_1d">
            <num>(1d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1d)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-34__subsec_1e">
            <num>(1e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1e)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code and deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-34__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1g)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-35">
          <num>71.35</num>
          <heading>Imposition of additional tax on tax-option corporations</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1L">
            <num>(1L)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1L)  “Qualified real estate investment trust” has the meaning given in s.71.22 (9ad).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1m)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1p">
            <num>(1p)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1p)  “Related entity” means any person related to a taxpayer as provided under section267or1563of the Internal Revenue Code during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year and any real estate investment trust under section856of the Internal Revenue Code, except a qualified real estate investment trust, if more than 50 percent of any class of the beneficial interests or shares of the real estate investment trust are owned directly, indirectly, or constructively by the taxpayer, or any person related to the taxpayer, during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year.  For purposes of this subsection, the constructive ownership rules of section318(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified by section856(d) (5) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall apply in determining the ownership of stock, assets, or net profits of any person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1r">
            <num>(1r)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1r)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “rental expenses” means the gross amounts that would otherwise be deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income for the use of, or the right to use, real property and tangible personal property in connection with real property, including services furnished or rendered in connection with such property, regardless of how reported for financial accounting purposes and regardless of how computed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1u">
            <num>(1u)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1u)  For purposes of s.71.34 (1g) (b), 2013 stats., “Internal Revenue Code” includes section 109 of division U of P.L.115-141.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(2)  “Tax-option corporation” means a corporation which is treated as an S corporation under subchapter S of the internal revenue code and has not elected out of tax-option corporation status under s.71.365 (4) (a)for the current taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(3)  “Tax-option item” means an item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(4)  “Wisconsin net income”, for tax-option corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, means net income and, for tax-option corporations engaged in business both within and outside this state, means the amount assigned to this state under s.71.25.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1)  It is the intent of this section that shareholders of tax-option corporations include in their Wisconsin adjusted gross income their proportionate share of the corporation’s tax-option items unless the corporation elects under s.71.365 (4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation or elects under s.71.365 (4m) (a)to be taxed at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1m)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(2)  A tax-option corporation shall separately state all tax-option items the separate treatment of which may affect the liability of any shareholder for tax under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(3)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(4)  Every tax-option corporation that is required to file a return under s.71.24 (1)shall, on or before the due date of the return, including extensions, provide a schedule to each shareholder whose share of income, deductions, credits, or other items of the tax-option corporation may affect the shareholder’s tax liability under this chapter.  The schedule shall separately indicate the shareholder’s share of each item.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(1)  All tax-option items of nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts derived from a tax-option corporation not requiring apportionment under sub.(2)shall follow the situs of the business of the corporation from which they are derived, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(2)  Nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts deriving income from a tax-option corporation which is engaged in business within and without this state shall be taxed only on the income of the corporation derived from business transacted and property located in this state and losses and other items of the corporation deductible by such shareholders shall be limited to their proportionate share of the Wisconsin loss or other item, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.  For purposes of this subsection, all intangible income of tax-option corporations passed through to shareholders is business income that follows the situs of the business, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1)  Adjusted basis of shareholders’ stock in tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1m)  Tax-option corporations; depreciation. For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2014, a tax-option corporation shall compute amortization and depreciation under the federal Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 2000, except that property first placed in service by the taxpayer on or after January 1, 1983, but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (b)and(br), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, and property first placed in service in taxable year 1981 or thereafter but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (bm), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, shall continue to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980.  Any difference between the adjusted basis for federal income tax purposes and the adjusted basis under this chapter shall be taken into account in determining net income or loss in the year or years for which the gain or loss is reportable under this chapter.  If that property was placed in service by the taxpayer during taxable year 1986 and thereafter but before the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter, the property’s adjusted basis and the depreciation or other deduction schedule are not required to be changed from the amount allowable on the owner’s federal income tax returns for any year because the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter.  If that property was acquired in a transaction in taxable year 1986 or thereafter in which the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferee is the same as the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferor, the Wisconsin adjusted basis of that property on the date of transfer is the adjusted basis allowable under the Internal Revenue Code as defined for Wisconsin purposes fo</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(2)  Corporation business loss carry-forward prohibition. The corporation net business loss carry-forward provided by s.71.26 (4)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(3)  Credits not allowed. The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation or shareholders of a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4)  Election to change from tax-option status.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-35__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-36">
          <num>71.36</num>
          <heading>Imposition of additional tax on tax-option corporations</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1L">
            <num>(1L)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1L)  “Qualified real estate investment trust” has the meaning given in s.71.22 (9ad).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1m)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1p">
            <num>(1p)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1p)  “Related entity” means any person related to a taxpayer as provided under section267or1563of the Internal Revenue Code during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year and any real estate investment trust under section856of the Internal Revenue Code, except a qualified real estate investment trust, if more than 50 percent of any class of the beneficial interests or shares of the real estate investment trust are owned directly, indirectly, or constructively by the taxpayer, or any person related to the taxpayer, during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year.  For purposes of this subsection, the constructive ownership rules of section318(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified by section856(d) (5) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall apply in determining the ownership of stock, assets, or net profits of any person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1r">
            <num>(1r)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1r)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “rental expenses” means the gross amounts that would otherwise be deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income for the use of, or the right to use, real property and tangible personal property in connection with real property, including services furnished or rendered in connection with such property, regardless of how reported for financial accounting purposes and regardless of how computed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1u">
            <num>(1u)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1u)  For purposes of s.71.34 (1g) (b), 2013 stats., “Internal Revenue Code” includes section 109 of division U of P.L.115-141.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(2)  “Tax-option corporation” means a corporation which is treated as an S corporation under subchapter S of the internal revenue code and has not elected out of tax-option corporation status under s.71.365 (4) (a)for the current taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(3)  “Tax-option item” means an item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(4)  “Wisconsin net income”, for tax-option corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, means net income and, for tax-option corporations engaged in business both within and outside this state, means the amount assigned to this state under s.71.25.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1)  It is the intent of this section that shareholders of tax-option corporations include in their Wisconsin adjusted gross income their proportionate share of the corporation’s tax-option items unless the corporation elects under s.71.365 (4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation or elects under s.71.365 (4m) (a)to be taxed at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1m)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(2)  A tax-option corporation shall separately state all tax-option items the separate treatment of which may affect the liability of any shareholder for tax under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(3)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(4)  Every tax-option corporation that is required to file a return under s.71.24 (1)shall, on or before the due date of the return, including extensions, provide a schedule to each shareholder whose share of income, deductions, credits, or other items of the tax-option corporation may affect the shareholder’s tax liability under this chapter.  The schedule shall separately indicate the shareholder’s share of each item.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(1)  All tax-option items of nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts derived from a tax-option corporation not requiring apportionment under sub.(2)shall follow the situs of the business of the corporation from which they are derived, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(2)  Nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts deriving income from a tax-option corporation which is engaged in business within and without this state shall be taxed only on the income of the corporation derived from business transacted and property located in this state and losses and other items of the corporation deductible by such shareholders shall be limited to their proportionate share of the Wisconsin loss or other item, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.  For purposes of this subsection, all intangible income of tax-option corporations passed through to shareholders is business income that follows the situs of the business, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1)  Adjusted basis of shareholders’ stock in tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1m)  Tax-option corporations; depreciation. For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2014, a tax-option corporation shall compute amortization and depreciation under the federal Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 2000, except that property first placed in service by the taxpayer on or after January 1, 1983, but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (b)and(br), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, and property first placed in service in taxable year 1981 or thereafter but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (bm), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, shall continue to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980.  Any difference between the adjusted basis for federal income tax purposes and the adjusted basis under this chapter shall be taken into account in determining net income or loss in the year or years for which the gain or loss is reportable under this chapter.  If that property was placed in service by the taxpayer during taxable year 1986 and thereafter but before the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter, the property’s adjusted basis and the depreciation or other deduction schedule are not required to be changed from the amount allowable on the owner’s federal income tax returns for any year because the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter.  If that property was acquired in a transaction in taxable year 1986 or thereafter in which the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferee is the same as the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferor, the Wisconsin adjusted basis of that property on the date of transfer is the adjusted basis allowable under the Internal Revenue Code as defined for Wisconsin purposes fo</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(2)  Corporation business loss carry-forward prohibition. The corporation net business loss carry-forward provided by s.71.26 (4)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(3)  Credits not allowed. The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation or shareholders of a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4)  Election to change from tax-option status.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-36__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-362">
          <num>71.362</num>
          <heading>Imposition of additional tax on tax-option corporations</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1p">
            <num>(1p)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1p)  “Related entity” means any person related to a taxpayer as provided under section267or1563of the Internal Revenue Code during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year and any real estate investment trust under section856of the Internal Revenue Code, except a qualified real estate investment trust, if more than 50 percent of any class of the beneficial interests or shares of the real estate investment trust are owned directly, indirectly, or constructively by the taxpayer, or any person related to the taxpayer, during all or a portion of the taxpayer’s taxable year.  For purposes of this subsection, the constructive ownership rules of section318(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, as modified by section856(d) (5) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall apply in determining the ownership of stock, assets, or net profits of any person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1r">
            <num>(1r)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1r)  For purposes of sub.(1k) (j)and(L), “rental expenses” means the gross amounts that would otherwise be deductible in the computation of Wisconsin adjusted gross income for the use of, or the right to use, real property and tangible personal property in connection with real property, including services furnished or rendered in connection with such property, regardless of how reported for financial accounting purposes and regardless of how computed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1u">
            <num>(1u)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1u)  For purposes of s.71.34 (1g) (b), 2013 stats., “Internal Revenue Code” includes section 109 of division U of P.L.115-141.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(2)  “Tax-option corporation” means a corporation which is treated as an S corporation under subchapter S of the internal revenue code and has not elected out of tax-option corporation status under s.71.365 (4) (a)for the current taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(3)  “Tax-option item” means an item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(4)  “Wisconsin net income”, for tax-option corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, means net income and, for tax-option corporations engaged in business both within and outside this state, means the amount assigned to this state under s.71.25.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1)  It is the intent of this section that shareholders of tax-option corporations include in their Wisconsin adjusted gross income their proportionate share of the corporation’s tax-option items unless the corporation elects under s.71.365 (4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation or elects under s.71.365 (4m) (a)to be taxed at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1m)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(2)  A tax-option corporation shall separately state all tax-option items the separate treatment of which may affect the liability of any shareholder for tax under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(3)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(4)  Every tax-option corporation that is required to file a return under s.71.24 (1)shall, on or before the due date of the return, including extensions, provide a schedule to each shareholder whose share of income, deductions, credits, or other items of the tax-option corporation may affect the shareholder’s tax liability under this chapter.  The schedule shall separately indicate the shareholder’s share of each item.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(1)  All tax-option items of nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts derived from a tax-option corporation not requiring apportionment under sub.(2)shall follow the situs of the business of the corporation from which they are derived, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(2)  Nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts deriving income from a tax-option corporation which is engaged in business within and without this state shall be taxed only on the income of the corporation derived from business transacted and property located in this state and losses and other items of the corporation deductible by such shareholders shall be limited to their proportionate share of the Wisconsin loss or other item, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.  For purposes of this subsection, all intangible income of tax-option corporations passed through to shareholders is business income that follows the situs of the business, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1)  Adjusted basis of shareholders’ stock in tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1m)  Tax-option corporations; depreciation. For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2014, a tax-option corporation shall compute amortization and depreciation under the federal Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 2000, except that property first placed in service by the taxpayer on or after January 1, 1983, but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (b)and(br), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, and property first placed in service in taxable year 1981 or thereafter but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (bm), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, shall continue to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980.  Any difference between the adjusted basis for federal income tax purposes and the adjusted basis under this chapter shall be taken into account in determining net income or loss in the year or years for which the gain or loss is reportable under this chapter.  If that property was placed in service by the taxpayer during taxable year 1986 and thereafter but before the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter, the property’s adjusted basis and the depreciation or other deduction schedule are not required to be changed from the amount allowable on the owner’s federal income tax returns for any year because the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter.  If that property was acquired in a transaction in taxable year 1986 or thereafter in which the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferee is the same as the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferor, the Wisconsin adjusted basis of that property on the date of transfer is the adjusted basis allowable under the Internal Revenue Code as defined for Wisconsin purposes fo</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(2)  Corporation business loss carry-forward prohibition. The corporation net business loss carry-forward provided by s.71.26 (4)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(3)  Credits not allowed. The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation or shareholders of a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4)  Election to change from tax-option status.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(1)  Special tax; computation. In lieu of the income and franchise tax rates prescribed in s.71.27, there shall be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable income of every corporation whose principal source (defined for purposes of this subchapter as being 50 percent or more) of gross income is the urban mass transportation of passengers a special income tax of 50 percent determined in accordance with this chapter, except that:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(2)  Determination of net business loss. The addition to and deductions from income of urban transit companies under sub.(1)shall be used in determining the Wisconsin net business loss of such companies to be offset against the Wisconsin net business income as determined under this section for purposes of s.71.26 (4).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1g)  “Corporation” means insurance corporations, insurance joint stock companies, insurance associations and insurance common law trusts, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1s">
            <num>(1s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1s)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-362__subsec_1sg">
            <num>(1sg)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sg)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing net income under the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-365">
          <num>71.365</num>
          <heading>Imposition of additional tax on tax-option corporations</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1u">
            <num>(1u)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(1u)  For purposes of s.71.34 (1g) (b), 2013 stats., “Internal Revenue Code” includes section 109 of division U of P.L.115-141.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(2)  “Tax-option corporation” means a corporation which is treated as an S corporation under subchapter S of the internal revenue code and has not elected out of tax-option corporation status under s.71.365 (4) (a)for the current taxable year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(3)  “Tax-option item” means an item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.34(4)  “Wisconsin net income”, for tax-option corporations engaged in business wholly within this state, means net income and, for tax-option corporations engaged in business both within and outside this state, means the amount assigned to this state under s.71.25.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1)  It is the intent of this section that shareholders of tax-option corporations include in their Wisconsin adjusted gross income their proportionate share of the corporation’s tax-option items unless the corporation elects under s.71.365 (4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation or elects under s.71.365 (4m) (a)to be taxed at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(1m)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(2)  A tax-option corporation shall separately state all tax-option items the separate treatment of which may affect the liability of any shareholder for tax under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(3)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.36(4)  Every tax-option corporation that is required to file a return under s.71.24 (1)shall, on or before the due date of the return, including extensions, provide a schedule to each shareholder whose share of income, deductions, credits, or other items of the tax-option corporation may affect the shareholder’s tax liability under this chapter.  The schedule shall separately indicate the shareholder’s share of each item.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(1)  All tax-option items of nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts derived from a tax-option corporation not requiring apportionment under sub.(2)shall follow the situs of the business of the corporation from which they are derived, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.362(2)  Nonresident individuals, nonresident estates and nonresident trusts deriving income from a tax-option corporation which is engaged in business within and without this state shall be taxed only on the income of the corporation derived from business transacted and property located in this state and losses and other items of the corporation deductible by such shareholders shall be limited to their proportionate share of the Wisconsin loss or other item, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.  For purposes of this subsection, all intangible income of tax-option corporations passed through to shareholders is business income that follows the situs of the business, except that all income that is realized from the sale of or purchase and subsequent sale or redemption of lottery prizes if the winning tickets were originally bought in this state shall be allocated to this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1)  Adjusted basis of shareholders’ stock in tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1m)  Tax-option corporations; depreciation. For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2014, a tax-option corporation shall compute amortization and depreciation under the federal Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 2000, except that property first placed in service by the taxpayer on or after January 1, 1983, but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (b)and(br), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, and property first placed in service in taxable year 1981 or thereafter but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (bm), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, shall continue to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980.  Any difference between the adjusted basis for federal income tax purposes and the adjusted basis under this chapter shall be taken into account in determining net income or loss in the year or years for which the gain or loss is reportable under this chapter.  If that property was placed in service by the taxpayer during taxable year 1986 and thereafter but before the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter, the property’s adjusted basis and the depreciation or other deduction schedule are not required to be changed from the amount allowable on the owner’s federal income tax returns for any year because the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter.  If that property was acquired in a transaction in taxable year 1986 or thereafter in which the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferee is the same as the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferor, the Wisconsin adjusted basis of that property on the date of transfer is the adjusted basis allowable under the Internal Revenue Code as defined for Wisconsin purposes fo</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(2)  Corporation business loss carry-forward prohibition. The corporation net business loss carry-forward provided by s.71.26 (4)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(3)  Credits not allowed. The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation or shareholders of a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4)  Election to change from tax-option status.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(1)  Special tax; computation. In lieu of the income and franchise tax rates prescribed in s.71.27, there shall be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable income of every corporation whose principal source (defined for purposes of this subchapter as being 50 percent or more) of gross income is the urban mass transportation of passengers a special income tax of 50 percent determined in accordance with this chapter, except that:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(2)  Determination of net business loss. The addition to and deductions from income of urban transit companies under sub.(1)shall be used in determining the Wisconsin net business loss of such companies to be offset against the Wisconsin net business income as determined under this section for purposes of s.71.26 (4).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1g)  “Corporation” means insurance corporations, insurance joint stock companies, insurance associations and insurance common law trusts, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1s">
            <num>(1s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1s)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-365__subsec_1sg">
            <num>(1sg)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sg)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing net income under the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-37">
          <num>71.37</num>
          <heading>Conformity</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(1m)  Tax-option corporations; depreciation. For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2014, a tax-option corporation shall compute amortization and depreciation under the federal Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 2000, except that property first placed in service by the taxpayer on or after January 1, 1983, but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (b)and(br), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, and property first placed in service in taxable year 1981 or thereafter but before January 1, 1987, that, under s.71.04 (15) (bm), 1985 stats., is required to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980, shall continue to be depreciated under the Internal Revenue Code as amended to December 31, 1980.  Any difference between the adjusted basis for federal income tax purposes and the adjusted basis under this chapter shall be taken into account in determining net income or loss in the year or years for which the gain or loss is reportable under this chapter.  If that property was placed in service by the taxpayer during taxable year 1986 and thereafter but before the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter, the property’s adjusted basis and the depreciation or other deduction schedule are not required to be changed from the amount allowable on the owner’s federal income tax returns for any year because the property is used in the production of income subject to taxation under this chapter.  If that property was acquired in a transaction in taxable year 1986 or thereafter in which the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferee is the same as the adjusted basis of the property in the hands of the transferor, the Wisconsin adjusted basis of that property on the date of transfer is the adjusted basis allowable under the Internal Revenue Code as defined for Wisconsin purposes fo</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(2)  Corporation business loss carry-forward prohibition. The corporation net business loss carry-forward provided by s.71.26 (4)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(3)  Credits not allowed. The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation or shareholders of a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4)  Election to change from tax-option status.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(1)  Special tax; computation. In lieu of the income and franchise tax rates prescribed in s.71.27, there shall be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable income of every corporation whose principal source (defined for purposes of this subchapter as being 50 percent or more) of gross income is the urban mass transportation of passengers a special income tax of 50 percent determined in accordance with this chapter, except that:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(2)  Determination of net business loss. The addition to and deductions from income of urban transit companies under sub.(1)shall be used in determining the Wisconsin net business loss of such companies to be offset against the Wisconsin net business income as determined under this section for purposes of s.71.26 (4).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1g)  “Corporation” means insurance corporations, insurance joint stock companies, insurance associations and insurance common law trusts, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1s">
            <num>(1s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1s)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1sg">
            <num>(1sg)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sg)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing net income under the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1sh">
            <num>(1sh)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sh)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_1t">
            <num>(1t)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1t)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-37__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(2)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-38">
          <num>71.38</num>
          <heading>Conformity</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(3)  Credits not allowed. The credits under s.71.28 (4m)may not be claimed by a tax-option corporation or shareholders of a tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4)  Election to change from tax-option status.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(1)  Special tax; computation. In lieu of the income and franchise tax rates prescribed in s.71.27, there shall be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable income of every corporation whose principal source (defined for purposes of this subchapter as being 50 percent or more) of gross income is the urban mass transportation of passengers a special income tax of 50 percent determined in accordance with this chapter, except that:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(2)  Determination of net business loss. The addition to and deductions from income of urban transit companies under sub.(1)shall be used in determining the Wisconsin net business loss of such companies to be offset against the Wisconsin net business income as determined under this section for purposes of s.71.26 (4).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1g)  “Corporation” means insurance corporations, insurance joint stock companies, insurance associations and insurance common law trusts, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1s">
            <num>(1s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1s)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1sg">
            <num>(1sg)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sg)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing net income under the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1sh">
            <num>(1sh)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sh)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_1t">
            <num>(1t)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1t)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-38__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(2)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-385">
          <num>71.385</num>
          <heading>Conformity</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(1)  Special tax; computation. In lieu of the income and franchise tax rates prescribed in s.71.27, there shall be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable income of every corporation whose principal source (defined for purposes of this subchapter as being 50 percent or more) of gross income is the urban mass transportation of passengers a special income tax of 50 percent determined in accordance with this chapter, except that:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(2)  Determination of net business loss. The addition to and deductions from income of urban transit companies under sub.(1)shall be used in determining the Wisconsin net business loss of such companies to be offset against the Wisconsin net business income as determined under this section for purposes of s.71.26 (4).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1g)  “Corporation” means insurance corporations, insurance joint stock companies, insurance associations and insurance common law trusts, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1s">
            <num>(1s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1s)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1sg">
            <num>(1sg)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sg)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing net income under the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1sh">
            <num>(1sh)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sh)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_1t">
            <num>(1t)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1t)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-385__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(2)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_71-39">
          <num>71.39</num>
          <heading>Conformity</heading>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_4m">
            <num>(4m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(4m)  Tax-option corporation election to pay franchise or income tax at the entity level.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(5)  Federal return copy. A tax-option corporation shall file with its state franchise or income tax return an exact copy of its federal income tax return for the same year and shall file any other return or statement filed with or made to, or any document received from, the U.S. internal revenue service, and any form required of that corporation and prescribed by the department of revenue, affecting the taxation of its shareholders.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(6)  Notice to shareholders of appeals and other proceedings. Except as provided in s.71.745, any notice of determination by the department of any tax-option item may be contested by a tax-option corporation under subch.XIV.  A tax-option corporation shall timely notify all shareholders of any administrative or judicial proceeding about the determination of any tax-option item.  Each shareholder may participate in any such proceeding and shall be bound by the final determination in that proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(7)  Qualified subchapter S subsidiaries. If a tax-option corporation elects to treat a subsidiary as a qualified subchapter S subsidiary for federal purposes, that election also applies for this chapter.  If this state has jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the qualified subchapter S subsidiary, this state has the jurisdiction to impose the taxes under this chapter on the tax-option corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.365(9)  Adjustment under rules. A corporation that elects under sub.(4) (a)not to be a tax-option corporation and a corporation that elects to become a tax-option corporation shall adjust its income, under rules promulgated by the department of revenue, for the taxable year for which that election is first effective to avoid the omission or double inclusion of any item of income, loss or deduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(1)  Special tax; computation. In lieu of the income and franchise tax rates prescribed in s.71.27, there shall be assessed, levied and collected upon the taxable income of every corporation whose principal source (defined for purposes of this subchapter as being 50 percent or more) of gross income is the urban mass transportation of passengers a special income tax of 50 percent determined in accordance with this chapter, except that:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.39(2)  Determination of net business loss. The addition to and deductions from income of urban transit companies under sub.(1)shall be used in determining the Wisconsin net business loss of such companies to be offset against the Wisconsin net business income as determined under this section for purposes of s.71.26 (4).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1b">
            <num>(1b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1b)  “Aggregate effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective tax rates imposed by a state, U.S. possession, foreign country, or any combination thereof, on the person or entity.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1g">
            <num>(1g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1g)  “Corporation” means insurance corporations, insurance joint stock companies, insurance associations and insurance common law trusts, unless the context requires otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1m">
            <num>(1m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1m)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1s">
            <num>(1s)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1s)  “Effective tax rate” means the maximum tax rate imposed by the state, U.S. possession, or foreign country, multiplied by the apportionment percentage, if any, applicable to the person or entity under the laws of that state, U.S. possession, or foreign country.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1sg">
            <num>(1sg)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sg)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “intangible expenses” include the following, to the extent that the amounts would otherwise be deductible in computing net income under the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2):</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1sh">
            <num>(1sh)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1sh)  “Intangible property” includes stocks, bonds, financial instruments, patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, mask works, trade secrets, and similar types of intangible assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_1t">
            <num>(1t)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(1t)  For purposes of ss.71.45 (2) (a) 16.and18.and71.255 (2) (d) 1., “interest expenses” means interest that would otherwise be deductible under section163of the Internal Revenue Code, as adjusted under s.71.45 (2).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="71-39__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>71.42(2)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>