<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WI-Statutes">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-72"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-72"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#wisconsin-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-wi"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72"/>
          <FRBRname value="WI-Statutes"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-72/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-72/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-72/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-wi/act/statutes/chapter-72/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="wisconsin-legislature" href="https://docs.legis.wisconsin.gov" showAs="Wisconsin State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_72">
        <num>72</num>
        <heading>Estate Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_72-005">
          <num>72.005</num>
          <heading>Purpose</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(1)  “Administration” means any proceeding relating to a decedent’s estate whether decedent died testate or intestate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(4)  “Circuit court” means the circuit court which has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(6)  “Death tax” is a tax imposed by a state, territory or district, because of a death or gift in contemplation of death, on property or a transfer of property, and includes estate, inheritance, succession, legacy and transfer taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(7)  “Decedent” means the deceased person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(8)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9)  “Distributee” means any person to whom property is transferred by reason of a death or in contemplation of death other than in payment of a claim.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9m)  “District attorney” means the district attorney of the county whose circuit court has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11)  “Estate” means all property of a decedent transferred by reason of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-005__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-01">
          <num>72.01</num>
          <heading>Purpose</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(1)  “Administration” means any proceeding relating to a decedent’s estate whether decedent died testate or intestate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(4)  “Circuit court” means the circuit court which has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(6)  “Death tax” is a tax imposed by a state, territory or district, because of a death or gift in contemplation of death, on property or a transfer of property, and includes estate, inheritance, succession, legacy and transfer taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(7)  “Decedent” means the deceased person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(8)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9)  “Distributee” means any person to whom property is transferred by reason of a death or in contemplation of death other than in payment of a claim.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9m)  “District attorney” means the district attorney of the county whose circuit court has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11)  “Estate” means all property of a decedent transferred by reason of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-01__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-02">
          <num>72.02</num>
          <heading>Purpose</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(1)  “Administration” means any proceeding relating to a decedent’s estate whether decedent died testate or intestate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(4)  “Circuit court” means the circuit court which has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(6)  “Death tax” is a tax imposed by a state, territory or district, because of a death or gift in contemplation of death, on property or a transfer of property, and includes estate, inheritance, succession, legacy and transfer taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(7)  “Decedent” means the deceased person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(8)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9)  “Distributee” means any person to whom property is transferred by reason of a death or in contemplation of death other than in payment of a claim.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9m)  “District attorney” means the district attorney of the county whose circuit court has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11)  “Estate” means all property of a decedent transferred by reason of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-02__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-03">
          <num>72.03</num>
          <heading>Purpose</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(1)  “Administration” means any proceeding relating to a decedent’s estate whether decedent died testate or intestate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(4)  “Circuit court” means the circuit court which has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(6)  “Death tax” is a tax imposed by a state, territory or district, because of a death or gift in contemplation of death, on property or a transfer of property, and includes estate, inheritance, succession, legacy and transfer taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(7)  “Decedent” means the deceased person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(8)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9)  “Distributee” means any person to whom property is transferred by reason of a death or in contemplation of death other than in payment of a claim.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9m)  “District attorney” means the district attorney of the county whose circuit court has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11)  “Estate” means all property of a decedent transferred by reason of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-03__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-045">
          <num>72.045</num>
          <heading>Purpose</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(1)  “Administration” means any proceeding relating to a decedent’s estate whether decedent died testate or intestate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(4)  “Circuit court” means the circuit court which has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(6)  “Death tax” is a tax imposed by a state, territory or district, because of a death or gift in contemplation of death, on property or a transfer of property, and includes estate, inheritance, succession, legacy and transfer taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(7)  “Decedent” means the deceased person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(8)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9)  “Distributee” means any person to whom property is transferred by reason of a death or in contemplation of death other than in payment of a claim.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9m)  “District attorney” means the district attorney of the county whose circuit court has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11)  “Estate” means all property of a decedent transferred by reason of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-045__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-06">
          <num>72.06</num>
          <heading>Definitions</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(1)  “Administration” means any proceeding relating to a decedent’s estate whether decedent died testate or intestate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(4)  “Circuit court” means the circuit court which has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(6)  “Death tax” is a tax imposed by a state, territory or district, because of a death or gift in contemplation of death, on property or a transfer of property, and includes estate, inheritance, succession, legacy and transfer taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(7)  “Decedent” means the deceased person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(8)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9)  “Distributee” means any person to whom property is transferred by reason of a death or in contemplation of death other than in payment of a claim.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9m)  “District attorney” means the district attorney of the county whose circuit court has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11)  “Estate” means all property of a decedent transferred by reason of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-06__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-11">
          <num>72.11</num>
          <heading>Estate tax imposed</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(6)  “Death tax” is a tax imposed by a state, territory or district, because of a death or gift in contemplation of death, on property or a transfer of property, and includes estate, inheritance, succession, legacy and transfer taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(7)  “Decedent” means the deceased person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(8)  “Department” means the department of revenue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9)  “Distributee” means any person to whom property is transferred by reason of a death or in contemplation of death other than in payment of a claim.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_9m">
            <num>(9m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(9m)  “District attorney” means the district attorney of the county whose circuit court has jurisdiction under s.72.27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11)  “Estate” means all property of a decedent transferred by reason of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-11__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-21">
          <num>72.21</num>
          <heading>Estate tax imposed</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_11m">
            <num>(11m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11m)  “Federal credit” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax credit allowed for state death taxes as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_11n">
            <num>(11n)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(11n)  “Federal estate tax” means, for deaths occurring after September 30, 2002, and before January 1, 2008, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on December 31, 2000, and for deaths occurring after December 31, 2007, the federal estate tax as computed under the federal estate tax law in effect on the day of the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_12m">
            <num>(12m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(12m)  “File” means mail or deliver a document that the department prescribes to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(13)  “The intestate laws of this state” include statutory rights and allowances to a child and to a surviving spouse and any other rights of a surviving spouse acquired by contract in lieu of any statutory rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_14m">
            <num>(14m)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(14m)  “Pay” means mail or deliver funds to the department or, if the department prescribes another method of submitting or another destination, use that other method or submit to that other destination.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-21__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-22">
          <num>72.22</num>
          <heading>Estate tax imposed</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(16)  “Personal representative” means any person to whom letters to administer a decedent’s estate have been granted by the court but does not include a special administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(19)  “Property” means any interest, legal or equitable, present or future, in real or personal property, or income therefrom, in possession and enjoyment, trust or otherwise, within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.01(21)  “Transfer” means the passing of property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-22__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-225">
          <num>72.225</num>
          <heading>Estate tax imposed</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-225__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-23">
          <num>72.23</num>
          <heading>Notice</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-23__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-235">
          <num>72.235</num>
          <heading>Timely filing</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-235__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-24">
          <num>72.24</num>
          <heading>Confidentiality of tax returns</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-24__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-27">
          <num>72.27</num>
          <heading>Subjects liable</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(1)  Residents and nonresidents.  A tax is imposed upon any transfer of property to any distributee in the following cases:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-27__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-30">
          <num>72.30</num>
          <heading>Personal liability</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.11(2)  Exception; reciprocity as to nonresident decedents.  A transfer, which is made taxable under this chapter and is of a nonresident decedent’s intangible personal property is not subject to the tax imposed by this chapter if a like exemption is allowed at the time of the death of the decedent by the laws of the state, territory or district of the decedent’s residence in favor of residents of this state or if the state, territory, or district of the decedent’s residence does not impose a tax on the transfer at death at the time of the death of the decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(1)  Each personal representative, special administrator, and trustee of a trust in existence and containing property on the date of the decedent’s death, is severally liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, to the extent of the clear market value of all property under the control of that personal representative, special administrator or trustee, the transfer of which is subject to this tax.  This liability extends to all taxes due under this chapter on all transfers to a distributee, and is not limited to the value of transfers of property in the control of the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.21(2)  A trustee of a trust which comes into existence after the decedent’s death and a distributee are liable for the tax imposed by this chapter, with interest, only to the extent of the clear market value of property transferred to the trustee or distributee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-30__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-33">
          <num>72.33</num>
          <heading>Installment payments; closely held businesses</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(1)  When payable.  Except as provided in s.72.225, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid on the date 9 months after the decedent’s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(2)  Advance payment.  Anyone personally liable for a tax under this chapter may pay an estimated tax before the tax is determined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.22(3)  Payment.  Except as provided in s.72.225, at the time that the return is filed, the full tax shall be paid.  If a prepayment was made, any additional tax shown owing on the return, as filed, shall accompany the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(1)  If a percentage of the federal tax on an estate may be paid in installments under section6166of the internal revenue code, the same percentage of the taxes under this chapter may be paid under the same installment schedule if written notice of the election to pay in installments is given to the department within 9 months after the decedent’s death.  The provisions on acceleration under section6166(g) of the internal revenue code apply to payments under this section.  The interest rate on payments is 12 percent and is calculated from the date of death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-33__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-34">
          <num>72.34</num>
          <heading>Acceleration and interest</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.225(2)  Upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), distributees of real estate shall provide the department a certified copy of a lien for unpaid taxes and interest on the property to secure payment, and shall record the lien in the office of the register of deeds of the county in which the property is located.  Distributees of personal property, upon the filing of a notice under sub.(1), shall either provide a lien or provide the department a financial guarantee bond equal to the estimated tax and interest elected to be paid under sub.(1)to secure payment if the tax has not been determined.  Upon determination of the tax, distributees of personal property shall provide a lien or provide a financial guarantee bond sufficient to secure payment of the tax and interest or pay the department the excess over the amount of tax and interest secured by the bond.  The department may accept a lien affecting only part of the property if there is sufficient security to secure payment of the tax.  Any distributee who fails to provide the security required under this subsection or who disposes of one-third or more of the property on which the tax is secured under this subsection, shall pay the tax in full.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-34__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-35">
          <num>72.35</num>
          <heading>Acceleration and interest</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(1)  If the tax imposed by this chapter is not paid when it is due under s.72.22, interest is due and payable at the rate of 12 percent per year from date of death.  In computing time under this section, the day of death is excluded.  If any payment of tax or interest under s.72.225is not paid when due, the tax and interest due shall be paid upon notice by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.23(2)  The department or circuit court may waive interest on any additional tax arising from the discovery of property omitted in the inventory of total assets or in the original tax determination, if due diligence was exercised in determining the assets.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(1)  Residents.  The circuit court for the county of which the decedent died a resident has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions arising under this chapter and to do any act authorized by a circuit court in other matters or proceedings coming within its jurisdiction.  If 2 or more courts are entitled to exercise jurisdiction, the court first acquiring it retains exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.27(2)  Nonresidents.  The circuit court of Dane County has jurisdiction to hear and determine all questions relating to the determination and adjustment of the tax imposed by this chapter, if a tax appears due because of the death of a nonresident decedent and in which it does not otherwise appear necessary for regular administration.  If a nonresident dies possessed of real or tangible personal property located within this state, the circuit court of the county in which the property is located shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the circuit court for Dane County.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(1)  Filing requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-35__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_72-36">
          <num>72.36</num>
          <heading>Adjustments</heading>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(3)  Certificate of tax.  Upon receipt of the return and payment of the tax, the department shall issue a dated certificate showing the amount of tax and any interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(4)  Hearing in circuit court.  The attorney general, department, district attorney or any person dissatisfied with the appraisal, assessment or determination of the tax due under this chapter may apply for a hearing before the circuit court within 6 months from the date the certificate in sub.(3)is issued.  The applicant must give a written notice to the court stating the grounds of the application.  No statute of limitations shall run against the department in cases of fraud or collusion or where property is not disclosed in the return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.30(7)  Collection.  In addition to its powers to collect taxes due under this chapter, the department may proceed in the manner provided in ss.71.91 (5)and(7).  All payments under this chapter after their due date shall be applied first in discharging costs and interest and the balance applied on the tax principal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(2)  A person who is entitled to a refund of the federal estate tax or liable for additional payments of that tax shall, within 30 days after receiving notice of that fact, do the following:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.33(3)  Any refund which the department finds due shall be made within 30 days after receipt of the report under sub.(2) (b).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(1)  Arbitration agreement.  When the department and the taxing authority of another state each claim that a decedent was a resident of its state on the date of the decedent’s death, the department may make a written agreement with the other taxing authority and with the personal representative, special administrator or trustee, to settle the dispute or submit the controversy to a panel consisting of any uneven number of arbitrators.  Parties to the agreement shall select the arbitrators.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(2)  Powers of the panel.  The panel may administer oaths, take testimony and subpoena witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents.  Subpoenas may be issued by any panel member.  When a person fails to obey a subpoena, any court of record of this state, upon application by the panel, may order compliance with the subpoena and may punish further failure to obey as contempt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(3)  Hearings.  The panel shall hold hearings at such times and places as it may determine, upon reasonable notice to the parties to the agreement, all of whom may be heard, present evidence and examine and cross-examine witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(4)  Majority vote.  Except when issuing subpoenas, all questions arising in the course of the proceedings shall be determined by majority vote of the panel.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(5)  Determination of residence.  The panel, by majority vote, shall determine the residence of the decedent on the date of the decedent’s death.  This determination shall be final only for purposes of imposing and collecting death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(6)  Filing of documents.  The panel shall file with each party to the agreement in sub.(1)and with the circuit court having jurisdiction under s.72.27a certified copy of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(7)  Compromise by parties.  The department may at any time enter into a written agreement to settle the controversy made under sub.(1)fixing the amounts to be accepted by the parties in full satisfaction of death taxes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(8)  Compensation and expenses.  Compensation and expenses of members of the panel and its employees shall be agreed upon among the members and the personal representative, special administrator or trustee.  If they cannot agree, compensation and expenses shall be fixed by the court which has or would have probate jurisdiction in the state determined by the board to be the residence of decedent.  The amounts agreed upon or fixed shall be an administration expense and shall be payable out of property transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="72-36__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>72.35(9)  Definition.  In this section, “state” means any state, territory, district or possession of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>